- [Instructor] Just like ship captains use the stars,
having the skills to navigate through software
is key to getting where you want to go.
In this lesson,
I'm going to walk you through the tools
that will keep you organized
as you create surveys and quizzes in Microsoft Forms.
Starting from the Microsoft 365 homepage,
I'll go to the app launcher and open Forms.
Here, I can create a new form,
view my recent forms, pinned forms,
and forms shared with me.
If I scroll to the bottom,
there is the My Group's pane
where you can see the groups you're a member of
and the total number of forms in each group.
What's important here at the bottom of my forms,
is the All My Forms button.
This will bring me to a list
with a list of all the forms I've created here.
You'll see the forms I've created
and the number of responses.
On the My forms page,
you have the ability to group your forms
into collections to keep them organized together.
New Collection is located on the upper right.
I created one collection that has my surveys.
Forms also gives you the choice of viewing a list or a grid.
This option is in the top right corner of your screen.
I like grid view
because I usually set a theme for each form,
making them easy to recognize and find.
With List View,
I can see all the forms I've created.
I can delete a form by clicking the More Options
in the lower right corner of a card and selecting delete.
I'll confirm by clicking delete.
If you need to restore a form that you've already deleted,
not to worry, you can get it back from the recycle bin
in the lower right corner.
Now you're ready to use Microsoft Forms
to choose the right tools to quickly navigate to your forms.
Try it out by logging into Microsoft 365,
go into the Forms app, and making your first form.