- [Narrator] You may not realize it,
but forms are used all the time in your daily life.
Everything from casting your vote
to filling out a feedback survey
from your favorite coffee brand,
forms are used to gather all kinds of data.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to use Microsoft Forms to make surveys,
quizzes, and sign up forms
to reveal any data you're looking for.
In the top left corner of office.com.,
I'll select the app launcher and open forms to get started.
Surveys gather data from clients
and can inform you of opportunities to improve.
For example, I use a survey every semester
to gauge my effectiveness as a lecturer.
Another great way businesses can use forms is
to collect information.
This is a t-shirt signup form.
Not only do you get information on a client's t-shirt size,
but you also get their contact information.
You can also use forms for event registration.
Having a single list of all the people
who are attending an event electronically is the best way
to stay organized.
By creating a survey
for all your company's event registrations,
you'll always be able to track down necessary information
like number of RSVPs and anything else you need
to create a seamless event.
While forms and surveys allow you to gather data,
you can also use quizzes to assess the knowledge
of your clients and coworkers.
Quizzes can be fun.
I've used this animal quiz icebreaker to engage
with my team at the start of a meeting.
You can easily assess quiz results
with the Microsoft Forms response tab.
Let's take a look at this animal quiz.
I can easily scroll through the results
to see which questions were the most difficult
and which were the easiest.
This is indicated on my screen by looking
for the questions that have the least number correct
or those that have the most number correct.
I can also see the results graphically for a quick glimpse
into how everyone is doing with the material.
You can also download the data in Excel or import the data
into your favorite reporting tool to do further analysis.
Microsoft Forms provide several opportunities
for you to gather information and assess data.
This week create a fun quiz
for your coworkers, clients, or students.
Getting data directly
from your audience can only serve to improve your work.