- [Narrator] Automation can free up your time and help keep
workflows on track and running smoothly.
In this lesson, I'll give you a preview of the benefits
of Power Automate and how automating tasks
can help your business.
Do you find yourself completing the same tasks
over and over throughout your day?
In many cases, automation can help save you time and energy.
Removing repetitive tasks from your workflow
is a possibility with Power Automate.
First, Power Automate has several templates to help you
sync your work in One Drive, send an email for new tweets
with a keyword, or notify you when a student submits
a response to a quiz.
No matter your field of work, Power Automate has the tools
to assist you in your daily tasks.
Power Automate is also a great tool
to keep your inbox under control.
You can save email attachments to OneDrive for business,
set up a flow to get approval for holiday requests,
or immediately respond to clients who fill out a form.
Power Automate also helps you
with your project management tasks.
You can easily assign tasks to specific team members,
track documentation statuses,
and create a daily summary of tasks in Microsoft planner.
Power Automate even helps you with your time management
by letting you block your calendar for important projects
with the push of a button.
Finally, Power Automate goes where you go.
If you need to quickly check in on a workflow,
you can do so through the desktop, web, and mobile versions.
It is truly an incredible tool.
So, if you're ready to boost your productivity,
explore Power Automate to see how it can help
streamline your work.