- [Christine] Learning how to manage data in Microsoft 365
is a key skill that will enable you to take
on any project with certainty.
Managing data might sound like a task
for computer scientists, programmers and librarians,
but nearly everyone in the workplace manages data daily.
Microsoft 365 has extraordinary tools
to help you manage your data like a pro.
My name is Christine Matheney
and I'm a program manager at Microsoft.
In this course, I'm going to show you how to gather,
organize and distribute data using data tools,
including Forms, Power Automate, Excel and Power BI.
You'll learn high level skills
including how to customize forms, create pivot tables
and even create reports in Power BI.
Learning how to manage data in Microsoft 365
is a key skill that will enable you
to take on any project with certainty.
Let's get started.