- [Instructor] Data has become the foundation
in which everyone worldwide makes decisions.
But as helpful as data can be,
at times it can be overwhelming.
Microsoft Power BI is a powerful data visualization tool
that can create reports and dashboards,
allowing you to tell a story with your data.
In this lesson, I'll share the benefits of using Power BI
so that you can further your data visualization skillset.
Microsoft Power BI provides a visual framework
for sharing data.
Power BI can help model the information,
leading to beautiful, intuitive, interactive reports,
helping your audience gain insights.
Power BI Desktop is free to download to your PC
from the Microsoft store.
Power BI connects directly to your existing
Microsoft 365 documents, stored in your OneDrive
or SharePoint.
Being able to visualize your data
will give you an advantage as you communicate
with your team and clients.
I encourage you to download Power BI and give it a try.