- [Narrator] It's essential for you to be able to sort
and manage your data so that the most important information
is right at the top.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to use Excel
to sort and filter your data
so you can quickly find what you need.
In the top left corner of office.com,
I'll select the app launcher and open Excel.
From here, I'll open
the sample sales order Excel spreadsheet.
You can find this document in your exercise files.
I'm interested in finding a specific order.
To use the search function, I'll use find and select.
Then I'll select find
and enter the sales order number.
Now select find next and Excel will highlight that row.
You can also use these functions to look
for specific items ordered by good toys.
Here, I'll enter good toys and select find all
to see all the rows with the information I'm looking for.
To find orders by customers more easily,
I'll sort the data by customer name.
First I'll select the column
then select sort and filter from the home ribbon.
Then I'll select sort ascending.
Let's say I want to see the sales from smallest to largest.
I will select the first cell in the total due column
then select sort and filter and sort ascending.
Excel also allows you to filter data.
Filtering data allows you to see only the data
you're looking for.
For this example, I'll use the order detail sheet
by selecting its tab at the bottom.
Let's say I'm looking for orders from good toys.
I can navigate to the data ribbon
and add filter headings by selecting filter.
A dropdown is added to each header for the column.
Now I can select the values for the filters.
First I'll select the company dropdown,
deselect select all, then select good toys and apply.
These are the orders for good toys.
I can add more customers by selecting other customers
in the company dropdown.
I'll add action bicycle specialist
before selecting apply.
Once I'm done, I can remove all the filters
by selecting clear filter from company on the dropdown.
Excel also helped you sort using multiple columns
in a table.
I'm going to sort by the customer
and then by the line total.
I'll go to the data ribbon and select custom sort.
The custom dialogue allows me to pick the column to sort
and the order of appearance.
I'll start with the company column.
To add another column, I'll select add
and then I'll specify line total, sort descending,
and then select OK.
This produces a table where I can see the cost of the items
each customer ordered sorted from largest to smallest.
Now you have a few new ways to find
and sort data using Excel.
Take some time to sort and filter your data.
It all comes down to knowing what you're looking for.