- [Instructor] Before you can start
creating cool visualizations,
you'll need to know the common functions,
and the screens used to import and review data.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to navigate Power BI Desktop,
and connect the importance of reports
to the structure of the program.
You can install Power BI on your PC
by going to the Microsoft Store,
and searching for Power BI.
When you open Power BI Desktop,
you'll see the start screen.
Here you can see what's new,
the Power BI blog,
forums and various tutorials.
On the left, it's a menu of options
where you can get data, access recent sources
or open other reports.
Once you close the window,
you'll be in the workspace.
At the top,
you'll see the home ribbon.
This ribbon contains the most common
Power BI functions.
New visual which adds a visualization
to your workspace.
Excel workbook to import data into the program.
And transform data to merge data.
On the left is a bar with three buttons
for the report, data and model screens.
Power BI starts on the report screen.
This is where you'll create visualizations.
I'll show you a report I'm working on
for my sales team.
You can download this in the exercise files.
It's called sales team visualization.
In my workspace,
there are three visualizations.
When I select the data tab,
I can see the data used to create this report.
This is the customer table.
It looks similar to an Excel table,
and on the right is a list of the other data sets
imported into Power BI.
Next I'll select the model tab.
This gives you a graphical representation
of your data and its relationships.
In this example,
you're looking at customers, their orders,
the order details,
and the products they purchased.
Now I'll switch back to the report screen.
On the right side of the reports workspace,
you'll see three panels,
filters, visualizations and fields.
You can use filters to modify your visualizations
to only show a subset of data.
Power BI allows users to easily
switch visualization type
by simply selecting the visual styles
from the visualization panel.
There are typical bar charts, pie charts,
as well as advanced charts.
The fields panel is where you select the data
you want to report on.
When you import data sources into Power BI,
they will show up in the field panel.
You will this panel to select fields
for your visualizations.
Finally, the report workspace is broken down
into different pages.
You can add more by selecting
the plus at the bottom.
So that's a quick tour of Power BI.
Start small and import data
from an Excel workbook into the program,
and get comfortable with the tool.
Try it out.