- [Instructor] Imagine you're staring at a table
in Excel and attempting to make sense
of the relationships between several sheets.
Working with data
means dealing with the variety of formats
it appears in.
In this lesson, I'll show you
how to use Power BI's intelligent import tool
to assist you in creating relationships
between several sources of data.
You'll be able to join data
to make it easier to work with.
You can install Power BI on your PC
by going to the Microsoft Store,
and searching for Power BI.
When you open Power BI Desktop,
you'll see the start screen.
I'll go ahead and close it.
I'll open the report I've been working on.
You can download this in the exercise files.
It's called customer sample report.
This report has a list of names and addresses
of my customers.
I also have a separate Excel spreadsheet
with their orders.
I want to combine these to create
a visual aid for the delivery team.
First, select Excel Workbook
from the home tab on the top ribbon.
Then browse for the sales order workbook,
which has two sheets.
You can download this in the exercise files,
it's called sales order.
Select both sheets then select load.
After both spreadsheets load,
you can see the tables in the field's panel
on the right.
Select model on the left menu,
and you'll see the relationship
Power BI found between the different tables
when it loaded both sheets.
A data model is the relationship
between the different data sources.
On the top ribbon,
select managed relationships.
Here I can see that sales order ID
is the common field
between the sales order detail table,
and the sales order header table.
Additionally, customer ID is the common field
between the sales order header table,
and the customer table.
Now all three of the tables are connected.
Let's explore the customer ID relationship
by selecting the second row,
and then edit at the bottom.
The cardinality field tells Power BI
which table has the primary record
for the customer ID column.
In our example,
the customer table is the primary record.
So each customer ID will appear once.
A customer will likely place many orders,
and therefore Power BI
sets the cardinality to many to one.
You can modify this if necessary.
I'll select, okay.
Then close.
Pulling data from multiple spreadsheets
is a breeze in Power BI.
You can easily create relationships
between tables by finding the common fields
in those tables,
which means you can create reports
across multiple tables.
Take some time to build relationships
in Power BI with your existing spreadsheets.
You've got this.