- [Instructor] Collaboration is key
to any business's successful model.
As business consultant and author, Ken Blanchard once said,
"None of us is as smart as all of us."
In this lesson, I'll show you how to share your form
with collaborators so that they can view,
edit, and review the results of your form.
I'll show use the two best options
for sharing with your team and organization
so you can decide which is best for you.
In the top left-corner of office.com
I'll select the app launcher and open Forms.
From here, I'll open the Wedding Planning
Consulting Interest form.
To share this form with someone's specific on my team,
I'll select Share in the upper right corner.
At the bottom is Share to collaborate,
and I'll select Get a link to view and edit.
If I select the Users with an Office 365 work
or school account dropdown two additional options appear.
I'll share this with only those who need it
by selecting Specific people
in my organization can view and edit.
I can now enter the team member
that will help me with this form, Isaiah.
Now, two people have access Isaiah and myself.
If instead, I want to share this form
with anyone in my organization, I'll change it
to People in my organization can view and edit.
Now, I can copy a link to send it
to my colleague Lynn for review.
So I'll copy the link and message it to Lynn.
Lynn and I can now collaborate
and get this form ready to send to prospective clients.
As you create forms, be sure to include
at least one other team member in the review process.
Co-creating and collaborating in Microsoft 365
is a great way to make sure
your forms are ready to share with the world.