- [Instructor] Creating custom forms
like surveys and quizzes is an efficient and organized way
to get the information you need from internal team members
and external collaborators.
In this lesson, I'll show you
how to collect information from your audience
by building a Microsoft Form using different question types.
In this example, I'm going to create a contact form
to drive new clients and vendors
to a wedding planning company.
In the top left corner of office.com,
I'll select the app launcher and open forms.
I'll select new form.
I'll start by adding a name and description.
I'll set the form title to
Wedding Planning Consulting Interest.
I want my client to feel welcome,
so I'll write a friendly description.
Thank you for your interest in Wedding Planning Consulting.
Please fill out the contact form
so we can make your wedding a memorable day.
It's important to preview your form
to make sure it appears as intended.
The preview button on the top right
allows me to see what the form looks like.
Here you'll see that the form title and description
match what I typed in.
Below the description,
you'll notice this disclosure statement.
Hi, Demo.
When you submit this form,
the owner will see your name and email address.
By default, a form is created to collect information
from people in your organization.
To change the setting,
select the back button in the top left corner of the page
to go back to the form design window.
Select more form settings in the upper right corner
and select settings.
I'll switch who can fill out this form
to anyone can respond so that clients can access the form.
Now I'll go back to preview and the message is removed.
Now that the form looks good,
I'll select back to continue creating my contact form.
Next, I'm going to add questions to the contact form
that will capture relevant information
about the future client
and the type of services they may be looking for.
A good place to start
is to ask for their contact information.
To add a new question, I'll select add new.
Here, I'm presented with four different question types.
Choice, text, rating, and date.
Choice is answering a multiple choice question.
Text is a fill in the blank question.
Rating is giving an opinion on a scale.
And date is when you specify a date from a calendar.
For contact information,
I'm going to create three text questions.
I'll select text and enter email address.
I'll do this again for first name and last name.
The next piece of information that would be helpful
is when the clients want to get married.
This type of data can be captured
with the choice question type.
I'll select add new, choice, and enter the text
when do you plan to get married?
In the options field, I'll enter these options.
Less than six months, six to 12 months,
more than one year, and I don't know.
As a wedding planner, I would also like to know
if the clients have already picked a wedding date.
You can have them enter it using the date question type.
I'll select add new, date, and enter
if you've already picked a date, enter it here
as the question.
And lastly, let's find out how comfortable the clients are
at planning things on a scale.
So, I'll select add new, rating, with the text
how comfortable are you planning events?
Five being the most comfortable.
I will then select the symbol dropdown and choose number.
In a matter of minutes, my interest form is taking shape.
Microsoft Forms gives you the power
to intentionally gather information
from clients and coworkers alike.
Take some time and explore the other options
in the input fields and consider how you can use them
to get the details you need.
You've got this!