- [Instructor] I love when I can quickly create lists.
With Microsoft Lists,
I'm able to consistently stay on top of what I need to do.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you the simplest way
to access the most important parts of Microsoft Lists.
I'll start from Office.com,
select the App Launcher and Lists.
Here, you can see the Lists homepage
with Favorites displayed first.
My Favorites contains the lists I've tagged as important.
Here, you see my Conference Plan list.
To add a Favorite, select the star icon
when hovering over any list.
I will hover over Spring wedding show
and select favorite this list
because that event is coming up soon.
As I complete projects or finish lists,
I can remove this list from Favorites by selecting the star.
When you need to look back on previous projects,
Recent lists can help you find them quickly.
To see all the lists you've created,
use the dropdown to the right of Recent lists
and select My lists.
I can now see all the lists I've created in a single page.
Harness the power of Microsoft Lists
by signing in and beginning to navigate
all the features in the app.
You'll be amazed by the improvements you'll make
in your project organization.