- [Instructor] How many lists do you use
to keep track of your life?
There's never a shortage of lists for work.
Things I need to do today,
Potential future clients, emails I need to send, and more.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you how to identify the benefits
of using Microsoft Lists
so that you can start thinking of ways to use it.
First off,
Microsoft Lists is a great tool for staying organized.
You can easily arrange your tasks
and to-do lists into a structured order.
I'll start from office.com.
Select the app launcher in the upper left corner
and open Lists.
For example, I make Weekly ToDo lists
to keep track of all the different items I need to complete.
If I get assigned a new task this week,
I'll simply open my ToDo list,
select add a new item, and then add the title.
Another benefit of Microsoft Lists, is availability.
You could access your list from your desktop,
your phone, on the web, and even from Teams.
And finally, Microsoft Lists seamlessly integrates
with Microsoft 365 apps.
Because Microsoft Lists runs in the Cloud,
you can feed data to other apps
without uploading or downloading.
From my ToDo list,
I'll select integrate in the top menu
and see all the Microsoft 365 apps
I can feed data into.
With Power Apps,
you can create an app using your list data.
Power Automate, allows you to automate your routine
using your list.
And Power BI, will let you create a visualization
using your list data.
Organization, availability, and seamless integration
Make Microsoft Lists a powerful tool
to keep you organized and moving forward.
So the next time you move to write down a list,
I encourage you to give Microsoft Lists a try.