- [Narrator] Think about the last event you attended.
Was it virtual or in person?
You may have received information beforehand to prepare
or a link to share photos of the event.
Now think of the preparation that had to happen
before the event.
The key to a great event is good planning,
and Microsoft Planner can help.
In this lesson, I'll show you some of the critical benefits
of using Microsoft Planner
and ways to utilize it for anything you need to plan next.
In this example, I'll show you how I used Planner
to organize a wedding.
I created buckets for each phase the team completes
to put the wedding together by the deadline.
Planner also keeps due dates clear.
Knowing when individual tasks are due,
helps me see the big picture of the timeline.
With Planner, you can enter the dates for the tasks
to be completed.
Here you can see, I have many tasks,
including some that have due dates.
Planner is also a great collaboration tool
that makes it easy to assign tasks to your team members.
Depending on the size of your project,
you may have many people working with you.
Each member of your team can be assigned tasks
that speak to their skills.
Here you can see I'm collaborating
with team members for this wedding.
We work together to complete tasks
and can see the progress of the event.
Schedule view lets us see if we're ahead or behind schedule
and if our team members need help completing a task.
Next time you go to organize an event
or track the progress of your business,
use Planner to stay organized.