- [Instructor] When you're managing a project,
you'll be tracking lots
of moving parts and tasks.
Microsoft Project has powerful work management capabilities
that can be used by both project managers
and team members alike.
In this lesson, I'll show you
Microsoft Project's key features.
The first feature I want to highlight in Project
is task dependencies.
A project is often made up of tasks
that depend on each other.
I'll start by opening the August wedding project
I've been working on
so you can see how Project lists the various pieces
that need to come together for the event.
For example, the determined budget task is dependent
on the discussion with the couple about wedding size,
location and scope.
Grid view is fine for listing out the tasks,
but with dependencies,
it's much easier to understand
the information using a timeline.
This view gives me the timeline
of when tasks are due and their dependencies.
Once dependencies are created,
I can see the critical path.
The critical path shows the specific tasks,
that if delayed, will delay the entire project.
By analyzing a critical path,
you can also identify how to shorten the project length.
To view the critical path,
on the top menu,
select Filters and toggle Show Critical Path on.
All the tasks highlighted in red need
to be completed on time to meet the deadline.
Microsoft Project will help you manage large timelines
and projects.
If you need to identify dependencies
or the critical path, check out Microsoft Project.