- [Instructor] It's natural that, over time,
a plan will evolve and change.
Plans are living documents.
In this lesson, I'll show you how
to communicate changes using Microsoft Planner.
From office.com in the top left corner,
I'll select the app launcher, then open Planner.
I'll start by opening the June wedding plan
that I've been working on.
Select More on the top menu then, choose Plan Settings.
First, I can update my plan to have
a different background, I'll select this one.
Next, select Notifications.
In the bottom section, I can see that Planner
is already sending me individual notifications for my tasks.
I want to increase transparency across my team,
and make everyone aware when tasks are completed.
Since I'm the group owner in the Group Email setting
I'll select Send email to the group
when a task is assigned or completed, then select Save.
Joni just notified me that the marriage license
has been obtained, I'll mark that task as complete.
Now, the whole team will receive
an email and we can notify the client.
Finally, I can share my public plan across my organization.
I'm onboarding a new hire and I want them
to be able to see what the team is working on.
I can select More and, in the dropdown,
choose Copy link to plan.
The link is copied to my clipboard.
I can now send it in a Teams message or email.
By creating visibility across plans,
your team can be even more effective.
Consider turning on notifications
and sharing your next plan.