- [Narrator] Often in life, getting to where you want to go
starts with setting specific achievable goals.
While some of those goals can be reached simply and quickly,
others require a lot of thoughtful planning,
energy, time, coordination, and execution.
Throughout your life and career,
you'll likely take on many projects.
Managing those projects isn't always straightforward.
There are often different tasks,
people involved, and steps in between.
My name is Christine Matheney,
and I'm a program manager at Microsoft.
In this course, I'm going to show you
how to use Microsoft 365 apps
to increase your project management skills.
You'll learn how to create
and share lists in Microsoft Lists,
develop a plan in Microsoft Planner,
and manage your project with Microsoft Project.
Microsoft 365 has extraordinary tools
to help you manage your projects like a pro.
Learning how to manage projects in Microsoft 365
will boost your ability to take on any task.
Let's get started.