- [Instructor] Once your data is in a list,
it's time to optimize it to be organized and efficient.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to use List functions that save time
and help you stay organized when managing projects.
I'll start from office.com.
Select the app launcher in the upper left corner
and open Lists.
To get started, I'll go to the checklist for wedding.
Let's start by adding dates to the List items.
To create a date column, I'll select add column
to the right of the last column
and select date and time.
I'll enter due date for the title
and this truly needs to be accomplished by
for the description.
Select save and the due date column is added.
I can also switch to edit and grid view
for another way to view data in Lists.
The edit grid view window is similar
to editing data in a spreadsheet.
I like using this view when I have a lot of data to enter
at one time.
To get started, I'll select edit and grid view
in the top left of the window.
From here, I can easily add multiple due dates.
When I select one of the due date cells,
Lists will display a calendar
so I can easily select the correct date.
I'll pick Friday for the first task
and select the following Friday
for the next two tasks.
To save my changes, on the top select exit grid view.
Next, let's look at creating other list views.
On the top ribbon, select the all items drop down
then choose create new view.
I want to create a calendar view
so I'll select calendar.
Let's name this view checklist due dates.
I want to create a calendar view
so I'll select calendar.
Lists automatically populates the start and end date fields.
I'll select create
and List switches to my new view.
Now you can view tasks by their due date
making it easy to see what's due when.
Now you know how to add dates and creative views
for your lists.
Experiment with different list views
to see which works best for your project.