- [Instructor] Once you create a project,
The next step is to add tasks.
I've found the easiest way
is to think of the big pieces first,
and then fill in the details later.
In this lesson,
you'll be able to use Microsoft Project
to add tasks, assigned tasks,
and set start and end dates.
In this example,
I'll create a client wedding project.
I'll start from Office.com
Select the app launcher
in the top-left corner and open Project.
Note that using Project for the web
requires an active subscription
to Microsoft Project.
Next, I'll select new blank project.
On the Project main page,
you can see the project name,
and three options for grid, board and timeline.
And on the right there's filters,
and group members and more actions.
Grid view shows the list of tasks
for the project and the common task properties.
Name, quick look, assigned to and duration.
To rename the project,
I'll select untitled project
in the upper-left corner,
and I'll enter client wedding.
I'll set the start date
to the first day of next month.
Select the X in the upper right corner
to close.
Next, I'll add some tasks by selecting
add new task and name them.
I'll now switch to the board view
by selecting board in the top menu,
and I can see all the tasks are in bucket one.
I'll select bucket one to rename this bucket
to catering.
I'll then add another bucket for venue
by selecting add bucket.
I'll drag the venue-related tasks
into the venue bucket.
Now that the project buckets are set with tasks,
I can assign them to members of my team.
First, I'll switch back to grid view
by selecting grid on the top.
Now I can assign tasks
using the assigned to column.
For the finalized venue task,
I'll select the assigned to column,
and enter Isaiah,
and select them from the dropdown list.
A dialogue appears
asking whether I want to add Isaiah
to the project group.
Select add a group,
then select create and assign.
I'll assign identify a caterer to Lynne
by entering her name in the assigned to column,
and selecting assign and add.
The next I need to add
is the duration of each task.
The duration is how long I expect
the task to take.
I'll select the duration column
for the have a tasting task,
and enter one to set the duration to one day.
I'll do the same for the other tasks.
Now, when I go back to the board view,
I see each task,
who it's assigned to,
and the number of days to complete.
Next, I want to set the start dates.
Select timeline on the top menu,
and notice that each task
begins on the first day of next month.
And that the length of the box
is set by the duration I entered.
I can drag each task to the correct start date,
or select it and enter it in the start field,
and select X in the upper-right corner to save.
Before you start your next project,
explore how project can map your tasks,
and help you collaborate with your team.