- [Narrator] You've reached the end of this course,
but this is just the start of your journey
using Microsoft 365.
Understanding project management
and organization applications,
like Lists, Planner, and Project,
will make a big impact
on how you take on your next challenge.
Microsoft 365 has many resources to help
make your professional life more productive.
I want to share a few of those resources with you.
You can check out Microsoft Support
for a variety of videos to help you refresh
and learn new skills.
You can also attend virtual workshops
and online classes,
hosted by the Microsoft Store.
There's a lot to explore in Microsoft 365.
Thanks for watching.
And I hope that you use these new skills
to become a better project manager.
I hope you consider these tools,
as you take on your next project.