- [Instructor] As a project manager,
I'm coordinating multiple projects throughout my day.
I need a way to manage my work
to achieve maximum productivity.
Becoming comfortable in Planner helps me stay on top
of my projects on a day-to-day basis.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you the easiest way
to access the most important parts of Microsoft Planner
so you can start managing your plans.
I'll start from office.com and select the app launcher
in the top left corner.
Then open Planner.
This opens Planner hub where you'll find all the plans
you have access to.
The navigation menu on the left is where I look to create
a new plan and find tasks assigned to me.
I've pinned the June wedding plan and below it is a list
of recent plans I've been working on.
The recent section shows the plans
I've opened most recently.
To find all your plans, select all.
Finally in the left menu, select assigned to me
to see a list of all the tasks that are assigned
to your account.
By default, my tasks are grouped by progress with buckets
for not started, in progress, and completed.
Tasks with a date highlighted in red are overdue,
making them easy to identify.
I can also use the group by dropdown in the top right
to sort my tasks by priority.
This way I can see which ones I should focus on first.
Consider an upcoming event you need to plan.
I encourage you to open the Planner app
and explore the features to optimize the efficiency
of your next event.