- [Instructor] Microsoft Project
has a wide variety of helpful tools.
In order to get the most out of these tools,
you need to know what they are
and where to find them.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to locate key features
within Microsoft Project.
I'll start from Office.com, select the App Launcher
in the top left corner, and open Project.
Note that using Projects of the web
requires an active subscription
to Microsoft Project.
The Project homepage is where you'll find all
the Microsoft Projects you have access to.
At the top, there's a new blank Project button.
I can also see two main sections
on the homepage: Favorites and Recent.
Favorites has all the projects I've tagged as important.
I'm currently working on the August Wedding project.
I can mark this project as a favorite
by hovering over the project and selecting Mark Favorite.
As I complete projects,
I can un-favorite them by selecting More Options
and choosing Remove From Favorites.
The Recent panel contains the projects
you've opened most recently.
When I need to look back
on previous projects, Recent helps me find them quickly.
As you work with Projects,
team members may share their projects with you.
You can see shared projects
by selecting the Shared With Me tab.
Finally, if you want to narrow your search
to see just the projects you've created,
filter by selecting the Created By Me tab.
Now only the projects I've created are displayed.
I encourage you to explore the Project interface
before creating your first project.
You'll be comfortable
with this Project management tool in no time.