- [Instructor] Big projects are achievable
when you've broken them down into smaller tasks
and have added dependencies
to see what needs to be done first.
In this lesson, I'll use an example client wedding project
to show how to add subtasks and dependencies
in Microsoft Project
so that you can stay on top of all the details.
I'll start from office.com.
Select the app launcher in the top left corner
and open Project.
Note that using Project for the web
requires an active subscription to Microsoft Project.
I'll open the Client wedding project.
I'm in grid view by default.
From here, I can start to break down some of these tasks
into smaller subtasks.
For example, I have Identify a caterer as a task,
but I know there are subtasks associated with this item.
I will add the subtasks.
First, I'll add Determine allergies as a task
by selecting Add new task at the bottom.
Place your cursor to the left
of the newly created task number.
Then drag the task below the Identify a caterer task.
Now to make Determine allergies a subtask,
I'll select More options and choose Make subtask.
I'll add one more subtask
and drag it below Determine allergies.
I'll assign these tasks to Lynne.
Select the Assigned to column for Determine allergies
and enter Lynne.
And in the Duration column, enter 5 days.
Repeat these steps for Finalize budget,
but instead enter 2 days.
Notice that the Identify a caterer task Duration
is now automatically set to 5 days,
since the larger Duration of the two subtasks is 5 days.
These tasks are dependent on each other,
meaning that one of the tasks needs to be completed
before the next task can be started.
In this case, Determining allergies must happen
before the budget can be finalized.
To create dependencies, I'll select Open details
on the Finalize budget subtask.
In the Depends on section, select Add dependency,
then choose Determine allergies.
Close the task panel by selecting the X in the top right.
Notice that the Duration for Identify a caterer
changed to 7 days, since Finalize budget can't start
until the Determine allergies task is complete.
You now have two more tools to manage your projects.
Use subtasks when you need to break down larger work items
into smaller tasks,
and dependencies to identify when tasks can't start
before another is completed.
Try out subtasks and dependencies
to help you organize your next project.