- [Instructor] Have you ever used Excel
to track a project?
With Microsoft Lists,
you can save time by creating a list
from an existing Excel document.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to import
your existing data into Lists.
I'll start from Office.com.
Select the app launcher in the upper-left corner,
and open Lists.
In this example,
I have a spreadsheet I've been using
for my wedding planning business,
and I want to bring it into Lists
for a more robust planning experience.
You can follow along by downloading
the wedding plan checklist
from the exercise files.
Start by selecting new list.
Now I'll select from Excel.
Select upload file and navigate
to the Excel document on your computer.
Then the wizard brings me
to the customized screen
where I'm instructed to select the table
from the file.
I'll check the column types,
and choose a new type
if the current selection is incorrect.
I will leave task as the title of the item.
For the when column,
I have a few categories, nine to 12 months
six to nine months.
So I'll select choice in the dropdown.
Then select next.
I'll set the name to checklist for wedding,
and I want to add a description.
So I'll enter wedding plan checklist
for 12 months to one week out.
I'll select the clipboard icon,
and select create.
Just like that,
the Excel data is imported into my new list.
Looks good.
But one thing isn't quite right.
The when choice column is not color coded
like choice columns usually are.
Select the dropdown next to when,
and select column settings then edit.
The edit column panel appears on the right.
I see that my choices were not imported
so I will add them manually
by selecting add choice.
My first time span is nine to 12 months.
So I'll enter that in the choice one box.
I will select the palette icon,
and set this as green.
I will repeat this for six to nine months,
four to six months and two to four months.
Choosing a new color each time.
I can save the choices I entered,
and the when column is updated.
By taking advantage of Lists ability
to import directly from an existing
Excel spreadsheet.
You have the power to transform,
and simplify a lot of data.
Now it's your turn.
Find an existing list you have in Excel,
and import it into Microsoft Lists.