- [Instructor] A paper notebook is bound by its cover,
but a digital notebook goes far beyond that,
building bridges to the rest of the internet.
With OneNote, you can use your notebook
as a portal to the worldwide web.
In this lesson, I'll show you
how to easily connect your notebook to any website
by adding links.
This can be really useful
when adding key information like a company's website
in your job search.
First, I'll open My job search notes notebook.
So here I am in the notebook
where I'm keeping notes about my job search.
I have created a template I can use
to keep track of each job I'm interested in.
I'm curious about jobs I might find at Microsoft.
So I'll use the template to create a page
for my job search at Microsoft.
I'll rename my page Microsoft search.
I'm not ready to search or make notes yet,
but I know there is a career site at Microsoft,
so I want to link my notes
directly to that useful information.
I can do this by adding a link to the page.
If I already know the web address, I can add it directly.
First I want to select where the link will go on my page.
I'll select Insert and Insert Link,
I'll type in the text I want to display for the link,
and then type in the web address,
and now I'll select Insert.
I can also go directly to the website in my browser
and select the web address,
then copy and paste it on my page in OneNote.
Now you can add links to pages in your notebooks
to make more dynamic connections
than you could with a paper notebook alone.