- [Joni] When you need to present
important ideas visually, PowerPoint is the tool
that takes your communication to another level.
In this lesson, I'm going to walk you through
how to create a presentation in PowerPoint and add
your first slide.
First I'll open PowerPoint.
And in this example, I've been selected
for a remote job interview and was asked to
create a PowerPoint presentation to showcase my skills.
So next, I'll select New blank presentation.
Before going too far I want to make sure
I've renamed and saved my presentation.
I can see the save status next to the title
of the presentation, and it is saved.
If I select the title, a new window opens,
and I can rename the presentation Interview slides.
After I renamed the presentation,
I can select anywhere outside the window and it will close.
I want to focus on adding content at the moment.
And so I'm going to close Designer.
The first slide is a title slide.
So I'll write the title, Skills overview.
Then I'll add my name under the title
so my audience will remember me.
I now have the first slide in my presentation and I'm ready
to add more slides.
Now, you know how to create a PowerPoint presentation.
Go ahead and try to add a slide to your own presentation.