- [Joni] Scrolling through an endless inbox
for that one email you need can feel like
trying to find a needle in a haystack,
but Outlook has a search tool that makes it easy
to find any email.
In this lesson I'm going to show you how to search
your email inbox.
I'll start in my Outlook inbox.
In this example, I have an interview for a job,
and the company has asked me to create a PowerPoint
presentation for my interview.
The company sent me an email with the presentation
instructions but I can't remember all of the requirements.
To be able to know exactly what's expected of me,
I'll need to search for this email in Outlook.
I remember the email had the word presentation in it.
So I'll go to the search box and type in
the word presentation then select Enter.
This searches my email for all the emails
with the word presentation.
Here's the email I was looking for.
I'll open it to see the requirements.
As you can see Outlook has also highlighted the search word.
If you wanted to narrow your search to only find emails
that have attachments, you could use Filter.
First, I'll navigate back to my Inbox.
I'll select the Filter button above my mailbox,
select Attachments, and now my mailbox is only showing
emails that have attachments
Now that you know how to search your email,
you'll be able to quickly find any email
even if it's buried deep in your inbox.