- [Instructor] Picture this.
You just updated your resume to apply for a new job.
All the details look great, except there's one problem.
Your resume's spread over two pages
and the job application asks for one page max.
By adjusting the margins,
you can keep everything on the same page
without deleting anything important.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to use margins
to fit the content you want in the space you need.
To get started, download the sample resume
available in the Exercise Files.
The first thing you need to do is open the resume.
Since this is such an important document,
make sure to review it closely
to make sure it has all the necessary information.
This layout looks good,
but there's a little bit of text
running onto the second page.
So to keep everything on one page without deleting anything,
you want to customize your margins.
I'll show you how by going up to the ribbon
and selecting Layout.
This is where Word displays several options
for how text is arranged on the page.
You can explore all these features on your own,
but for now, just select Margins.
From here, you can choose pre-made margins
or Custom Margins.
I'll choose Custom Margins to give myself more flexibility.
When I select Margins,
a window appears showing the current margins.
The bigger your margins are,
the less room you'll have for text on a page,
but making them smaller will allow you
to fit more text in the same space.
Since I need to fit all the text
onto a single sheet of paper,
these margins need to be smaller.
I'll lower the default margins from one inch
down to a half an inch.
After selecting OK
to apply the updated margins to your document,
the resume now fits on one page.
If you need to adjust the margins again,
you can always go back into Custom Margins
and make any changes you need.
Now you know exactly how to adjust the margins
in a Word document
and get everything you need on the same page.
You're ready to reformat your resume
or any other document.