- [Joni] Have you ever witnessed a presentation
that was so text-heavy,
you didn't know where to focus your attention?
Not a fun experience.
Formatting texts into different fonts and colors
can help your audience clearly understand
your presentation's message.
In this lesson, I'll show you how you can use PowerPoint
to change the appearance of your presentation's text
so that your audience can keep their focus
on the most important information.
In this example,
I open PowerPoint to add to the presentation
I'm creating for an upcoming job interview.
You can follow along by downloading the sample presentation
from the Exercise Files.
Now that I have my presentation open,
I want to change the font color,
so I'll select change font color from the menu,
then choose the color I want
and watch my highlighted text change to that color.
Next, I want to italicize the text.
With the text highlighted,
I'll select italics from the menu.
Looks great.
Now you can alter the look of any text you add
to a PowerPoint to help your presentation stand out.