- [Instructor] Have you ever finished
describing the steps of a complex task
only to realize it would've been simpler
to arrange the steps in another order?
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to apply slide layouts
and change the slide order
so your PowerPoint presents and flows perfectly.
In this example, I open PowerPoint
to start adding to the presentation I'm creating
for an upcoming job interview.
You can follow along by downloading the sample presentation
from the exercise files.
I already have two slides created,
and I want to add a new slide
that shares some information about myself.
I'll choose a title and content slide
to show this information.
I'll title it About Me.
Then, I'll add a few highlights to introduce myself
and my background.
I love helping people.
I've recently completed a customer service training.
Now that I see the slide,
I think I'd like to change the layout
to leave room to add a picture later.
I can select Layout to see my options.
I'll change the current layout to Two Content.
Hmm, this slide order doesn't seem right.
I think I want the About Me slide
to go in front of my skills slide
so my audience gets to know me before my skills.
To change the slide order,
I'll select View
and make sure I'm in the Normal view setting.
In the Normal view setting,
I can see the image of my slides
on the slide and the navigation pane.
I can go to the navigation pane
and select the About Me slide,
then drag and drop it above my skills slide.
My slides are now in an order that makes sense.
So that's it.
Now, you can change the slide layout and the slide order.
Use this skill to reframe how you share information
in any of your PowerPoint presentations.