- [Instructor] Sometimes an email can say it all,
but for those times
when you need to say a bit more,
attaching a file can help you add
even more important information.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you how to use Outlook
to send attachments
so that you can easily include
relevant files with your email
To show you how to use attachments,
I'm going to use the example
of trying to look for a new job.
I heard of a new opportunity,
and I'll need to attach my resume
to an email to share it.
First, I'll open Outlook.
From my Outlook inbox,
I'll open the email that I need to reply to.
I'll select reply,
and then I'll select add attachment.
A menu opens to help me find
the file I'm looking for.
Since I saved my document to Microsoft's
file hosting service OneDrive,
I'll select browse cloud locations.
I'll navigate to the file I'll need.
Select it and select next.
Now I can choose if I want to share a link
to my file or a copy of it.
If I was working on editing the file
with someone else,
I would share a link,
that way we could work on the file together,
and see updates in real time.
Since I'm sharing my resume
with a potential employer,
and we don't need to collaborate on the document,
I will choose attached as copy.
My resume is now attached to my email.
I'm ready to send it.
So I select send and my email and attachment
are on their way.
Try adding an attachment to your next email.