- [Instructor] Keeping a consistent composition
throughout a PowerPoint presentation
allows your audience to focus
on the important ideas you're presenting
without getting distracted.
In this lesson I'm going to show you
how Designer can help you
create a consistent look throughout your presentation
keeping your audience's attention
on your PowerPoint's content,
not its composition.
So first I'll open my presentation in PowerPoint.
You can follow along by downloading
the sample presentation
from the exercise files.
In this example,
I've already created a presentation
that I've been asked to prepare
for an upcoming interview.
Now, I want to change the look
of the presentation by using Designer
to get started.
Now that I'm in my presentation,
I'll select Designer.
Wow.
Look at all of these different looks.
I'll find a design I like
and choose it.
Now that I've chosen a design,
I can add a new slide.
I'll select the dropdown
beside the New Slide icon,
then I can choose the layout
of the slide I want to add.
I'll add a Two Content slide,
giving me a layout with space
for the title and two types of information.
I'm going to add a new title
and name this slide, Software skills,
then add text in one of the content sections.
By using Designer,
my entire presentation will have a consistent look
that will keep my audience's attention
on my skills.
I encourage you to explore design ideas
and choose a look for your presentations
that will wow your audience.