- [Instructor] Data is everywhere in the digital world.
With so much information on your screens and in your life,
it can be tough to keep track of everything.
What's great about Excel is that once you have your data
on a table, it's much easier to organize
and locate what you're looking for.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you how to sort your data in a table
to find the information you need.
To get started, download and open
the sample budget exercise file in Excel.
Now that I have the document open,
you can see that expense items
and amounts are already formatted as a table,
but they're not in any particular order.
I want to see my most expensive expense.
So I'll need to use sort and filter.
Sorting allows you to organize the data in a specific order.
To sort my data, I'll go to the header of my table
and select the Filter and Sort button
on the column I want to sort.
In the menu that appears,
I can choose from a variety of ways to sort the data.
Because I want to see my most expensive items first,
I'll select Sort Largest to Smallest.
Now, the expenses are sorted
from the highest expense to the lowest expense.
Sorting in this way can come in handy
when prioritizing which expenses
have the highest impact on a monthly budget.
In addition to sorting expenses by cost,
you can also sort them by name.
To sort by name, return to the top of the items column,
select Filter and Sort, and choose Sort A to Z.
Now, instead of the list being in order
from most expensive to least,
the budget items are sorted alphabetically.
This is useful if you have a long list of items
and you want to find one by name.
You can also filter the data in a table.
Filtering allows you to more easily see the data
you're looking for by temporarily limiting what's visible.
For example, I can filter my table
to only show the expenses that are $200.
Simply select the Filter and Sort button,
deselect Select All,
and select $200 and select Apply.
This will show only the expenses that are $200.
I can select
Select All to select all of my expenses again.
Now that you know how to sort and filter data in Excel,
you can arrange any type of data
in a way that works for you.