- [Instructor] Accessing, organizing, and using notes
in a paper notebook can be really challenging.
OneNote is a digital notebook
that makes your information work for you.
In this lesson,
I'm going to walk you through creating a notebook in OneNote
so that you can keep your information organized, useful,
and accessible from anywhere, anytime.
For job seekers, it's necessary
to keep track of detailed information
on each job you search for.
In this example,
I'll show you how to create a notebook in OneNote
to help with that important task.
First, in the top left corner of office.com,
select the app launcher and open OneNote.
Now that I've opened OneNote,
it's time to create a new notebook.
Select the Add new notebook option
and give the new notebook a name.
I'll name my notebook My job search notes,
and then I'll select Create.
After the notebook is created,
it's time to organize content by adding sections.
When you open a brand-new notebook,
you'll see this alert that the notebook is empty
with no sections.
In OneNote, every notebook is made up of sections
and each section has pages.
Think of these sections like dividers
between loose-leaf papers and a physical binder.
To add a section, I'm going to select Add section.
A window opens, asking for a section name.
Let's say I'm looking for two types of jobs,
one working as an office assistant
and the other as a teaching assistant.
These are different jobs.
So I'll separate my notebook
into an office assistant section
and a teaching assistant section.
I'm most interested in the office assistant job,
so I'll start with that section.
I'll name this section office assistant and select OK.
So now I have a new section in my notebook
called office assistant.
When a new section is created,
OneNote automatically adds a page called Untitled Page,
which I'll update here
to specify what type of notes I'll include.
Let's say job details.
Now that this page is set up,
I'm ready to take notes on the job opportunity.
Now that you know how to create a notebook
and sections within it,
you can make your own digital notebooks.
These will be places
where you can keep notes on job searches,
classes you're taking,
or which new series you want to binge watch.