- [Host] Believe it or not,
there are still many reasons
why a file living on your computer, tablet or phone
needs to jump off the screen and onto a sheet of paper.
Perhaps you need to add a handwritten signature
to an agreement or give a hard copy of your resume
to a hiring manager.
In these situations, you just need to press print.
After watching this lesson,
you'll know the steps to print your word documents,
bringing them off the screen and into the physical world.
A common document that needs to be shared physically
is a job resume.
So I'll walk you through how to print using a sample resume.
To begin, download the sample resume
available in the exercise files and open it up.
I won't be able to make any changes
once this resume is printed on a piece of paper.
So I want to take a moment to review my resume
and make sure I'm ready to press print.
Once I'm certain that this document is exactly how I want,
I'll go to the ribbon and select file.
From here, you can choose to create a new file,
open an existing file, save, share, export, or print.
To hold a copy of this document in my hand,
I'll need to choose print and then print this document.
Now a new screen appears that displays an image
of what the printout will look like,
as well as additional options and settings on the left.
Next, make sure the destination is set
for the correct printer.
With the destination set correctly,
and the preview looking right,
you are just about ready to print.
Leave the pages option to all.
If you had a multi-page document,
you'd use this option to specify
which pages you wanted to print,
but that's not right for my resume.
So I'll leave it as one.
At this point, if you select print,
the printing process will be underway.
If you want to go beyond a standard print
you can select print using system dialogue,
where you can change the layout of your document
from portrait to landscape, print only specific pages,
or make any other advanced adjustments.
Printing your documents is less common with PDFs and email,
but it's still a great way to make sure your document
looks exactly how you created it.
When you print a document,
you're bringing your digital work into the physical world
and that's amazing.