- [Instructor] Office Online is a free version of Office
that you can access from your web browser,
regardless of the operating system you're using.
In your browser, navigate to Office.com,
and click Sign in.
Using Office Online requires you
to have a free Microsoft account.
If you don't yet have an account,
you can click the Create one option
to create an account right away,
and use any existing email address you have.
Just be aware that it has to be a personal email address
and not one associated with your work or school.
But if you already have an account,
you can enter your username and password.
After signing in,
you'll see this screen where you can access all of the apps
that make up the Office Online package.
These online versions don't have all the same features
as the desktop versions,
but you can still accomplish a lot online.
For example, to use Microsoft Word, click its icon,
and that launches Word.
From here, you can choose to create a new document
from scratch by clicking New blank document,
or you can use any of the other templates
to start working from.
You can open an existing file from your OneDrive account,
which is Microsoft's cloud-based storage service,
where you can store and work with files
in all of the Office apps.
Saving your files to OneDrive
from Office Online allows you to continue working
on those files in the desktop versions of the apps later.
To work in any other app,
click the launcher button here
in the upper left-hand corner,
and select the app you want to use.
So now I've opened Excel Online,
and I can create a new blank workbook
to start working in an Excel spreadsheet.
Again, Office Online is free and offers a convenient way
to access your files and documents from various devices
and while on the go.