- [Instructor] When you first start up your computer,
the first thing to load is the operating system.
For example, Windows 10 is the most recent version
of the Windows operating system that comes pre-installed
on many PCs and tablet devices.
Here we'll explore the basics of navigating
around an operating system using Windows 10,
but many of these concepts carry over
to other operating systems as well.
When you start started the computer,
you'll usually see a screen to log into your account
on that computer.
Generally, it's a good idea for each person
using a computer to have their own account
rather than sharing an account between multiple users.
Individual accounts allow each user to keep their files
and work secured and organized
and let users personalize their experience on the computer.
For example, one user could set the computer
to display text in English
while another user could set it to display in Spanish
and because accounts are secured by passwords,
neither user can see the other's documents or other files.
To log into the computer, select your username,
or sometimes you'll enter it manually
and then type in your password.
In Windows 10 when you set up your account,
you also have the option of setting up
a personal identification number or pin
which you can enter instead of your password.
So you'll either enter a password or a pin
in this case, I'm entering a password
and I'll press Enter on my keyboard
and that's going to log me into the computer.
Once you're logged in, the first thing you see
is your computer desktop.
Similar to a real physical desktop,
your computer desktop is where you store files
you're currently working with.
In most operating systems, you can personalize
the look of your desktop by changing the background image,
sometimes called the wallpaper or by changing the colors.
At the bottom of the Windows 10 desktop is the task bar,
which is an essential tool for working
with the Windows operating system.
Depending on how you have it set up,
in the task bar you can see what apps are currently running,
what the current time is,
what appointments are on your calendar and so on.
On the far left of the task bar,
you'll find the Start button.
Clicking it opens up the Start menu
and this is where you can find
all the applications installed in your device.
This is also where you'll find the buttons to log off,
restart and shut down the computer.
For now, let's click outside the Start menu
to close it without selecting anything.
Next to the Start button is the search box
where you can search for applications by name
or search for files and documents on your device.
Using the search box can be a lot quicker
than manually looking for applications in the Start menu.
Just start typing the name of the application
or document you want to work with
and Windows will display the search results as you type.
For example, if I wanted to quickly open the calculator app,
I could just start typing calculator,
there it is, and I can just press Enter on my keyboard
to open that up.
Next to the search box, you'll see icons for applications
that are currently running or pinned to the task bar.
Pinned applications are apps that you can place
in the task bar to quickly access again
so you don't have to dig through the Start menu
to find them each time you want to open them.
Applications that are currently running
have a line underneath them
so you can easily tell if they're in use
as you can see here under the calculator icon.
To pin an application to the task bar,
place your mouse cursor over it
and then click the right mouse button on your mouse
or pointing device, this is referred to as right click,
which often brings up a menu containing several options.
In this case, I'll choose to pin the calculator app
to the task bar since I use it a lot.
So now even if I close the calculator app
by clicking the X button here in the upper right corner,
notice this icon stays in the task bar.
We no longer see the blue line under it
because it's not running, but I can easily click
to open the calculator app from here now.
Also here within the pinned and running apps
is File Explorer.
Clicking that opens up a window you can use
to browse the files on your computer
and I'll just close that.
The last section of the task bar is here on the right.
Here you usually see the date and time
along with various other icons
depending on how the computer's task bar
has been customized.
Clicking on icons can give you more information
about the computer.
For example, clicking on the clock, displays the calendar,
clicking on the network icon
shows you the status of your network connection.
Clicking this arrow here reveals other icons
that may be hidden so the task bar isn't cluttered
with too many icons at once.
So for example, from here, I can click the speaker icon
and that allows me to adjust the volume
of the computer speakers.
So that's the task bar in Windows.
Now, when you're done using your computer,
it's usually a good idea to log out of your account
or to shut down the computer
if you don't need to leave it running.
To do so, click the Start button.
If you just want to log out, but leave the computer running,
for example, if someone else needs to log into their account
to use the computer, just click the user icon
at the top here, and then choose a Sign Out.
That will log you out of your account,
but leave the computer running
so someone else can sign into their account.
Ultimately, you can click the power button here
and from here, you can shut down or restart the computer.
Choose to Shut Down if you want to shut down the computer
so it's not using any power.
And restart shuts down the computer
and immediately starts it again.
Sometimes restarting can fix issues
that may crop up while using the computer.
Again, we've been looking at the
Windows 10 operating system in this video,
but many of these concepts like searching for applications,
accessing settings and logging out and restarting
apply to other operating systems as well.