- These days the term computer can refer
to many different types of devices.
We have desktop computers, laptop or notebook computers
and mobile devices like tablets and phones
are even considered computers.
At the most basic level, a computer is an electronic device
that you use to create, process, store, or retrieve
different types of data and information.
For example, you might create a word processing document
on a desktop computer or browse the internet
on a tablet device, or email photos from your mobile phone.
All computers consist of two main parts,
hardware and software.
Software refers to the programs that run on the computer.
Basically software programs are the parts of the computer
you can't physically touch,
like a word processing application, an email program
and even the computer's operating system is software.
Most computers come with built in software
and you can install a virtually unlimited number
of other software programs that you might want
or need to use on your computer.
Now, hardware refers to all the physical parts
that make up a computer.
For example, on a desktop computer,
you have the main unit that contains the central parts
like the CPU, the RAM or memory, and the hard drive.
With desktop computers, you also need an external monitor,
also called a display and devices for inputting information
like a keyboard and a mouse.
On computers like laptops, tablets, or mobile devices,
the display is built into the device
and they all generally have built in keyboards
or, as is the case with many tablets and mobile devices,
the keyboard appears on screen when needed.
Computer hardware can also refer to any number
of accessories you can connect to the computer
such as printers, scanners, speakers, and so on,
which give additional functionality to the computer.
So again, when we talk about computers
at the most basic level,
we're talking about an electronic machine comprised of
various pieces of hardware
on which you can operate various pieces of software.