- [Instructor] In addition to the applications you use
on your desktop or laptop computer,
you'll probably also spend a lot of time
working with apps on your mobile phone or tablet.
Apps behave similarly on mobile devices
compared to desktop apps,
but you'll often find more limitations to mobile apps
in terms of power, functionality and ease of use.
Now, this isn't to say that you can't get work done,
play games and perform other tasks on your mobile phone.
You definitely can.
And apps for mobile devices
are usually designed specifically
for optimizing the experience of using a smaller screen
and a virtual keyboard.
Mobile apps are generally good for brief periods of work,
especially on phones.
Tablets with their larger screens
are more suitable for extended periods of work.
But with the prevalence of wifi
and cellular connections on mobile devices these days,
it's easy to not just to work and play on a mobile device,
but also to continue your work on a desktop computer later.
For example, let's say I'm working on a document here
in Microsoft Word on my phone during my morning commute.
It's a little difficult to see, but I can zoom in.
And when I need to make edits,
I can just tap on the screen and a keyboard will appear.
Now, I have this document saved over the internet
to my OneDrive account, which is a cloud-based service
I can store my documents on.
Then, later, when I arrive at my office,
I can open up the desktop version of Word
and here open the same document from OneDrive
and keep working on it.
But now, on a much larger screen
with a full range of editing tools
found in the desktop version of Word.
Or I might add a lunch meeting to my calendar
here in Microsoft Outlook on my computer.
But later, on my commute home,
I realize I need to change the appointment to another day.
I can open up the mobile version of Outlook on my phone,
see all of my appointments and make my changes.
You'll find that many work and productivity apps
now have this ability to sync over the internet
so you can work seamlessly between devices,
making your mobile devices
an extension of your desktop computer, in a sense.
But lots of mobile apps are also designed
as standalone apps on your phone or tablet,
apps that are designed for a quick check of the weather,
or for finding driving directions,
or to check on the status of a flight.
Probably one of the biggest differences
between mobile and desktop apps
is that while you can acquire desktop apps
through many different places,
like the Microsoft Store or an app developer's website,
or purchase physical copies of applications in a store,
although, that's becoming less and less common,
mobile apps, on the other hand,
are acquired only through dedicated stores
like the Google Play Store
for apps that run on Android mobile devices,
and the Apple App Store
for apps that run on Apple's iOS mobile operating system.
These mobile app stores are your one-stop location
for every app you may want to install on your device.
You can browse through multiple categories,
or use the search feature to find specific apps.
When you select an app, you can read about its features,
check out reviews from people who have used the app.
And if you want the app,
you can download or purchase it to immediately install it.
Once apps are installed, you'll find their icons
among all the other apps you have on your device,
and you can tap them to start using them right away.