- The first step to working with spreadsheets
in Microsoft Excel is to open an existing workbook
or to create a brand new one.
You can start from scratch with a completely blank workbook
or use one of the many available templates
included with Office to create workbooks
for making calendars, managing budgets, generating invoices,
and lots more.
To create a new workbook, open Excel.
And with the Home tab selected,
you can click Blank workbook
to instantly create a new empty spreadsheet
and start entering content into the cells right away.
Or to create a new workbook based on a template,
from here, go to File,
and then select New.
And below the blank workbook option,
you'll find a large collection of templates to choose from,
and you can scroll to browse through the templates.
Or you can scroll back up and type a search term
to look for online templates.
I'll search for budget.
And you can see these are all budget related templates now.
Click any template to get a closer look
and to read a description.
And when you find a template you'd like to use,
click Create.
Let's zoom out a little here so we can see the whole thing.
Now, the advantage of using a template like this
is that it already includes formulas
to perform these calculations.
You'll be able to see the numbers
and this Percentage bar updating as I make changes.
Once you started making changes
or adding content to your workbook,
you should save it so you don't lose those changes.
One way to do this is to click File and then Save as.
Then choose a location to save the file.
If you have a OneDrive account set up,
you can save to your OneDrive folder
to save your document to the cloud
so you'll be able to access it from anywhere
on any device running Excel.
Or you can choose to save it locally
to the computer you're currently using by choosing Browse.
Navigate to the location on your computer
where you want to save your file.
My Documents folder is currently selected,
which is where I'll leave it.
Then name your file.
I'll keep the current name of Monthly Food Budget
and I'll click Save.
So it's now saved to my Documents folder,
and I can see that if I go to the Start menu
and select Documents to open up that folder
and there it is.
So now I can continue working on my spreadsheet
here in Excel.
As you work, it's a good idea to periodically save your file
to make sure you don't lose your changes.
Once you've saved your file the first time,
you can quickly save it again by clicking the Save button
at the top of the Excel window.
So that's how to create and save a new workbook in Excel.