- Digital skills can play a powerful role
in helping you to connect, learn, engage with your community
and create a more promising future.
Working with computers can open doors
for opportunities at work,
connect you with friends or family,
spray your creativity, and expand your career horizons.
This series of lessons is designed
to help you improve your current skills
and also learn new skills to help you succeed
in the digital world.
We'll start with a look at computer and device basics
and find out what makes a computer a computer.
We'll look at how to use the operating system
to open, create, save, and otherwise manager your files,
applications, and projects.
Then we'll look at how to connect peripherals
like Bluetooth devices and external storage devices.
And we'll also explore productivity software applications
for work or personal use with tools like Word and Excel.
If you're new to computers
or have always felt a mild anxiety,
or even dread when you've sat down in front of a computer,
this course is for you.
We're going to avoid technical jargon
and discuss everything in easy to understand terms,
all while building your knowledge level
from a foundation of the very basics.
I'm Garrick Chow and welcome to this course
on working with computers and devices.
Let's get started.