- [Instructor] In addition to using Word
on your desktop or laptop computer,
you can also install the mobile version of Word
on your iOS or Android smartphone or tablet.
This gives you the ability to access and edit your documents
and stay productive from virtually anywhere.
Just go to the app store on your mobile device.
If you're on an Apple iPhone or iPad,
you'll open up the app store app.
If you're using an Android device,
open the Google Play store app.
Then do a search for Word,
select it, and from here, you can download
and install it on your device for free.
So here you see Word on my iPad.
Be aware that Word may look a little different
depending on the device you're using,
but the functionality is nearly identical
across all mobile devices.
For a specific details, you can visit support.office.com
in your web browser, and search for your device
by typing something like Word for iPad,
and you'll see a list of results.
So to use Word on your mobile device,
signing with the same account
you use for Office on your desktop or laptop computer.
Be aware that to access basic features of Word,
you don't need an Office subscription,
but a subscription doesn't lock all of the editing features
of Word on your mobile device.
And once I'm signed in, I can use Word anytime.
I need to start a new document,
or work on an existing one without having to wait
to get back to my computer at home or at the office,
I'll create a new document
by clicking the blank document template.
And now I can start typing.
Now, in this case, I'm typing with the onscreen keyboard,
but if you have an external keyboard
connected to your mobile device,
you can use that to allow for more visible area
for your document on screen.
You can then format the text
just like you can in the desktop version of Word.
For instance, I could select this heading,
and then go to the styles menu, and apply heading one.
Now you can see the top of the screen.
My document currently has the default name of document.
I want to give it a more descriptive name
so I know what this document contains later.
So I'd have the file icon here
in the upper left hand corner and tap save.
And I'll rename this to give any more descriptive name.
This is also where I can choose the location
to save the file. If I want to be able to access it later
from another device or a computer,
I could save it to my OneDrive account online.
Or alternately, if you know you won't have wifi
or internet access available as you're working,
you can save the file to your device instead of OneDrive,
so you can continue working on it while you're not online.
You can always save it to OneDrive later,
or to another location
once you've connected to the internet again.
In this case, I'll just choose to save it on my iPad,
and I'll tap save.
And now I can continue working on my document.
As you work, Word saves your changes automatically,
so you don't have to worry about remembering to save
as frequently as you may have to using the desktop version.
So with the mobile version of Word,
you have the freedom to work anywhere
and capture your ideas in writing.