- [Narrator] An important part of making sure your computer
and its programs continue to run smoothly
is to periodically check for and install updates
to your operating system.
For example, both Microsoft and Apple
frequently release updates to their Windows
and Mac OS operating systems,
often fixing bugs and adding new features.
To check for updates in Windows 10,
go to the start menu,
to settings, and select update and security.
Make sure Windows update is selected
and then click check for updates.
As long as you're connected to the internet,
Windows will check for system and security-related updates.
If any updates are available,
you'll see the progress of them being downloaded
and you'll have the option to install them,
which often involves restarting your computer.
So it's a good idea to make sure you're not working
in other applications or on any projects
when you're checking for and installing updates.
You can see I currently see this message
saying that I'm up to date,
meaning there are no system or security updates available,
but notice there is a feature update available
to my version of Windows 10.
And if I'm ready to install that,
I can click download and install now to begin that process.
And you can see now we'll go through the process
of updating Windows.
But again, if you don't see any available updates,
it means your computer is already up to date.
But you can still check back here periodically
to see if any updates have been released.
Again, it's a good idea to install updates
to make sure your computer continues to run smoothly.