- [Instructor] If you're working in a word document
that contains a lot of text and you need
to replace a word or sentence,
you can use the built-in Find and Replace feature.
This can be useful, for example,
if you realize you've been spelling someone's name wrong
throughout the entire document,
or some new information has changed some data
in your document that you now need to update.
Under the Home tab here in Word,
you'll locate the editing section.
And this is where you'll find the Find and Replace buttons.
So for example, I've noticed in this document
about the history of the Landon Hotel
that the founder Arthur Landon's name is misspelled
in a couple of different places.
You can see here the name is spelled with an A
instead of an O.
It would be time consuming
to read through the entire document
to locate each instance of this mistake.
So instead, I'm going to click the replace button.
In the Find What field, I'll type the word
that I'm looking for, which is the incorrect spelling
of Landon and in the Replace field,
I'll type the correct spelling of the name.
At this point,
you have a few options on how to find or replace this text.
If you click Find Next,
the first instance where it finds of the spelling
will be highlighted.
If I want to fix this instance, I click Replace.
I move this out of the way.
You can see that's now been fixed.
Word then jumps to the next instance.
But since I know that I want to correct all the instances
of this misspelling, I can click Replace All,
and Word will automatically change every instance
in the document.
And I get this notification telling me
that it made three replacements.
I'll click Okay.
And I'll Close.
So that's the find and replace feature in Word.
And again, it can be a big time saver,
especially in longer documents containing a lot of text.