- Let's take a look at how to connect your computer
to your network via a wired Ethernet connection.
Now, this assumes that your network has already been set up
in your home, office, or classroom.
If you're connecting to your home network,
you're most likely going to run an Ethernet cable
from your computer directly into your router.
If you're connecting in an office or classroom environment,
chances are you'll be running an Ethernet cable
from your computer into an Ethernet port on the wall
or some other fixture,
which in turn connects to your network.
In any case, the important thing is
that you have a cable running from whatever the source
of your network connection is
into the Ethernet port on your computer.
Nearly all desktop computers have built-in Ethernet ports,
though you're not seeing them as much on laptops these days,
as in the past.
If your laptop doesn't have Ethernet
or if you're using a tablet or a mobile phone,
you'll connect wirelessly to your network,
which we'll look at how to do later.
This case, though, I'll just plug the cable
that's running from my desktop's Ethernet port
right into my router.
And once you have your computer connected
to your network via Ethernet,
chances are you're already on your network
and you're so-called setup is done.
In most cases, once you connect your computer
to your network with an Ethernet cable,
you'll automatically be connected to the network and be able
to communicate with other computers on the network,
as well as access the internet.