- [Instructor] Keeping everyone on the same page
makes any team more efficient.
But when new members join,
valuable time can be wasted in bringing them up to speed.
With Microsoft Teams,
modifying who's part of your team is simple and easy.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to add team members
and manage their roles in Teams.
To show you how, I've created a team
for a conference I'm working on.
To bring everyone together to collaborate,
I need to make sure they are added to the team.
I'll start on the main Teams page.
To find the Skills conference team,
I'll use the menu to select teams from the sidebar.
Here you can see a list of all my teams.
I'll navigate to the Skills conference team
and select More options.
Then select Add member.
Since I'll be adding new members that are already a part
of my organization, I'll be able to add them
by typing in their name or email address
and then selecting Add.
To add people outside of your organization
is a little different.
You still add them using their email address
but they will be added to the team as a guest.
Guest roles cannot be changed.
When someone inside your organization is added to a team,
their initial role is member.
But you can change their role to owner, if you want.
Owners have the same permissions as members
but can also delete your team
and add or remove team members.
You can change a member's role to owner
by selecting the dropdown menu next to their assigned role.
In case the team needs editing when I'm away,
I'll add my colleague, Isaiah, as an owner.
Now that you can add team members to a team
and assign their roles,
you can start gathering the right people together
to collaborate on a project or event.