- [Narrator] The best workplaces are filled with
collaboration, teamwork and shared activities.
Positive results come from a team
where everyone works towards a shared goal.
Each member knows their role and responsibilities,
and clear communication
makes collaborating something to look forward to.
But how do you facilitate that with a modern team?
With Microsoft 365, of course.
I'm Courtney Hodge, a Program Manager at Microsoft,
and I'm passionate about helping people use technology
to make their lives easier.
In this course,
I'll give you the tools to maximize Microsoft Teams
to support your communication and collaboration.
I'll teach you how to use SharePoint
to work with your team and create engaging sites
to get people excited about events or programs.
I'll show you how to integrate these tools
into your team's workflow and how to gain new efficiency
in everything you do at work.
I don't know about you,
but group projects were never my favorite in school.
But learning to utilize Microsoft Teams and SharePoint
makes working with your team easy and efficient.
So if you're ready
to take your teamwork to the next level,
let's jump right in.