- [Instructor] Building a team takes time.
You need to transfer or recruit the right members,
build relationships and trust each other.
On the other hand,
creating a team in Microsoft Teams
takes hardly any time at all.
In this lesson,
I'll use an upcoming event I'm working on,
the skills conference,
to show you how to set up a team,
using templates to save even more time.
Let's jump in.
Once I'm in Teams,
I'll select teams from the left menu.
Then select join or create a team from the bottom.
If you were joining a team
that someone else had created,
you might be given a code to join a specific team
and you'd select join a team.
Since this conference
doesn't have a team set up already,
as the manager, I'll need to create one.
So I'll select create team.
I can either create a team from scratch
or from a template.
I see a manage an event template
which will work great for this.
I'll select that option to get started.
Here, Teams will display an overview
of the channels and apps associated with that template.
Just select next to continue.
Next up is the privacy level.
Because I don't want anyone to access my team
without me inviting them,
I'll make it private.
For naming the team,
I want to be brief, but descriptive.
Since I'm planning a conference,
I'll name it skills conference.
I'll also include a description
to give the members a way to know
what the team is about.
Like all templates,
this one comes with pre-made channels.
Think of a channel
as a place to talk about a specific topic.
When I manage events,
I need to create channels
where the whole team can discuss broad topics
and other channels where smaller groups
can talk about specific subjects.
If I expand customize channels,
I can see all the channels for this team.
The general channel is automatically created
with every team and cannot be deleted.
Most of these other channels are useful here,
but my team won't be a part of
any budget related conversations,
so I'll rename that one technology
since our conference will be hybrid this year.
I can rename the channel by selecting budget,
and replacing the channel name.
I can save my change
by clicking on customize channels.
At this point, everything is set up
and I'll select create team.
Now, it does take a little while
for a team to get set up
so just be patient
and come back a little bit later.
As you can see,
it doesn't take much effort
to create a team.
When you're able to create a team,
you're in a position to start streamlining communication
and collaboration for your next event or project.