- [Instructor] SharePoint can do many things:
run websites, store files, host resources,
all from your browser.
In this lesson, I'll show you SharePoint's key features
so that you can use it with confidence.
To get started, I'll open SharePoint using a web browser.
Organizations use Microsoft SharePoint
for a number of reasons.
SharePoint is an app that you connect to through
your web browser for a variety of purposes.
Not only can you use it to create websites,
you can also use it as a secure place to store, organize,
share, and access information from any device.
I want to use SharePoint to share presenter files
and resources for a skills conference
I'm planning with my team.
To get started, in the top left corner of office.com,
select the app launcher and open SharePoint.
I am now at my SharePoint start page.
In the top left corner of the SharePoint start page,
you'll see options to create sites or create a news post
if you want to make an announcement.
On the navigation bar on the left,
you can easily access your SharePoint start page,
the sites you're a member of, new news posts
from your sites, and your SharePoint files.
In the middle of the page is the News from sites section.
This is where you'll find news from the sites
that you're a member of.
If you see an article you'd like to view later,
simply add it to your reading list
by selecting the bookmark icon on the article.
Once bookmarked, the article is added
to your Saved for later section
found in the pane on the left.
Directly under News sites is a section
that displays your most frequently used SharePoint sites
and the recent activity on each of those sites.
You can favor a site here by selecting the star
in the upper right corner.
This will add the site to your Following list.
Now that you know your way around SharePoint,
you're ready to use your SharePoint start page today.