- [Instructor] Time is precious.
When your team is frequently using a document,
you can save everyone time
by adding that document to a tab.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you how to add tabs to your channels
to help your team get to their most needed content swiftly.
For this example,
I've already opened Teams
and created a team to collaborate on an upcoming conference.
I'm working on a skills conference with my team.
I've already created a team with specific channels,
but I want to make it even easier for my team
to collaborate and complete their work.
My logistics team is constantly using
and adjusting the rooms
that will be used for the skills conference.
Everyone is collaborating in the same file and that's great.
The file is in the files tab for my logistics channel,
but I want to make it even easier for them
to access this frequently used file.
So I'm going to add this file as a tab
in the logistics channel,
so it can be accessed with one step.
First, I need to go to my logistics channel.
Then, I'll go to the files tab
and select "show actions" next to the file name.
A window will pop up
giving me several actions I can take with this file.
I can open it, copy it, rename it, and more.
But for right now, I just want to make this file a tab,
and so I'll select "make this a tab".
The file is now a tab in my logistics channel
making it easy to access by everyone in the channel.
You can add a variety of tabs in your channels.
To see all the available options
for adding tabs in your channels,
select the "add a tab" button.
You can add websites, files from different apps,
like Word, OneNote, Excel, and PowerPoint.
There's so much to explore.
Adding tabs to your channels is easy.
Try it out to make it easier for your team
to access the items they need quickly.