- [Instructor] Communication is key
to the success of any team.
Using text-based messages to communicate is efficient,
fast and keeps everyone in the loop.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to post messages
in all your Team's channels
to keep your teammates connected.
For this example, I've already opened Teams
and created a team to collaborate on an upcoming conference
that we're all working on together.
I want to communicate to everyone on my Microsoft Team
by welcoming them and sharing how excited I am
to work on this event.
To do this, I select my announcements channel.
Starting from the post tab, I'll select new conversation
and I can begin my announcement.
I want to make sure I get my team's attention.
You can use mentions to send a notification
to an individual, a channel or a team.
I'll mention the entire team by entering @Skills conference
and selecting the team.
Now I can type in my message.
And now I can click send.
By mentioning the Skills conference team,
I've ensured that everybody in the Skills conference team
received a notification that I've posted this message.
In addition to sending a notification to an entire group,
I can also get the intention of an individual.
When posting in a channel, everyone can see
and respond to the post.
If there's a message that should be private,
sending a direct message or chat is best.
I want to ask Joni to share the draft planning document
with the team in the planning channel.
I'll navigate to the planning channel
and select the posts tab.
I'll start a new conversation
and I'll use the @ symbol and type in Joni's name
to mention her in my post.
Using mention ensures that Joni gets a notification
that I've posted.
Now that you know how to communicate with messages
in a channel and how to draw attention
to your messages using mentions,
practice these techniques
to streamline your communication with your team.