- [Instructor] There will be times
when you'll want to share news,
a status update on a project
or maybe you want a page
where people can learn more about an event
or program.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to create
a SharePoint communication site,
and show you how to use these sites
with your team.
From my SharePoint start page,
I'll select create site.
I want to share information,
and engage other viewers.
So I'm going to choose to make this
a communication site.
I'll name the site skills conference page.
For right now, I'll leave the description blank
because I'll come back later,
and describe the site's purpose.
After I've named my site, I'll select finish.
After I select finish,
I land on my new communication site,
and from here I can edit content.
I want to get everyone excited
about the upcoming skills conference.
So I'm going to use this site
to share information
to build anticipation for the event.
The site has one page so far, the homepage.
I like the look of this homepage,
but I want to see if templates
will offer me other options.
So I'll go to the upper right-corner,
and select settings.
I have several options to choose from here.
The first thing I want to do is apply a site template
to help change the overall layout of my site.
So I'll select that.
Once the select a template window opens,
you have several templates to choose from.
If you hover over a template and select details,
you'll get a clearer picture of the site layout,
and what the site is used for.
I want to see more details
on the showcase template,
so I'll select details.
I like the look of the showcase layout.
So I'll select use template.
I've created a communication site
using a template.
I'll need to add content to this site
before I'm ready to share it with others,
but I'm off to a super start.
Now you know how to add a communication site
in SharePoint.
Soon you'll be ready to add content,
and share your site with others.