- [Instructor] In the workplace,
you don't always have the time
or a quiet space to take a phone call,
so chatting can be a lot more practical.
Using the chat feature
in Teams allows you to have a flexible conversation
when you want to reach out
to people in your organization quickly.
In this lesson,
I will show you how to use Teams to easily
and quickly communicate.
In this example, I'll show you what to do
if I wanted to reach out to a teammate
just to check in on the status of a meeting,
let's go.
Once I'm in Teams, I'll select Chat to get started.
I have quick access to my recent chats here,
but if you want to start a new chat
or can't find the chat you need in your recent chats,
you can select the New Chat button.
As a chat window opens,
you can enter who you want to send the chat
to, either a specific individual
or a group, simply type in the name or email
of the person you want to chat with and select their name
or email to add them to the chat.
From here, you can also add more people.
If you want to remove anyone from the message,
you can select the X next to their name.
At this point, I can begin typing in my message.
Isaiah is working with me on an upcoming skills conference.
I want to know if Isaiah is planning to come
to the planning meeting next week.
So I'll just send him a message to ask.
I'll type in my message.
Then select Send.
I've now sent my message,
and I can continue working and wait for Isaiah to respond.
Once Isaiah responds, I get a notification,
and I can also find the activity in chat.
Now that you know how to communicate with chats and teams,
you can feel confident
in reaching out to anyone in your organization.