- [Instructor] Upload, download, rename, delete,
all this file management is key to your workflow,
but what's the best way to keep your shared files
inside Microsoft Teams organized?
Folders.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to enhance
your team's organization and workflow
by creating new files and folders in Teams.
For this example, I've already opened Teams,
and created a team to collaborate on
in an upcoming conference.
I'm working on a skills conference with my team.
I've created a draft flyer
for the presenters of the conference,
but I don't yet have a draft flyer for attendees.
So I first want to set up folders
to keep my flyers organized.
A flyer is a marketing tool.
So I'll first go to the marketing and PR channel.
Next, I'll select the files tab.
Now I can set up the folders for the files
to go into.
I need folders to separate the marketing
for attendees and presenters.
So I will create those new folders
by selecting ad new and choosing folder.
I'll name my folder, attendee marketing,
and select create.
I've now created a folder
in the marketing channel
for attendee marketing files.
I'll do the same for presenter marketing
by once again selecting ad new,
choosing folder,
and I'll name this folder presenter marketing,
and select create.
While in the files tab,
I want to go into the attendees marketing folder,
and click the folder.
This takes me to the content of this folder.
It's empty right now
since I just created the folder.
Now, from inside this folder,
I can create the new file.
I'll select new,
and then select PowerPoint presentation.
I'll name this presentation
draft attendee flyer.
Once I select create,
it takes me to my new PowerPoint presentation.
I use PowerPoint for flyers
just to use the designer features.
I can use the navigation pane on the left side
to get back to the files tab
for my marketing channel.
And if I go to the attending marketing folder,
I can see my presentation.
Now you can create and organized files in Teams.