- [Instructor] Sometimes you need your message to stand out.
A larger font, different colors, or maybe something more,
all these make your message clearer.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to edit
the formatting of your Team's post to highlight your message
and make key items more apparent.
Since I am responsible for planning a skills conference
with a team of people,
it will be a great example to show.
For this example,
I've already opened Teams and created a team to collaborate
on an upcoming conference
that we're all working on together.
I've created a team
to streamline our work and communication,
but I also want to share some upcoming tasks
that need to be completed.
I want to use some additional formatting features
to add to my post.
So I'll go to Announcements and select new conversation.
Then select format.
From here, I'll change and edit the announcement
before I post it.
I'll use a heading in bullets
to share the action items for the week.
The Mention feature is used to get the attention
of people or groups for specific action items.
Since I want the marketing and PR group
to have a draft flyer,
I'll mention this group in the first item in my list.
I want Joni to set up a call for the team.
I can mention her and ask her to set up a call.
I'll make this the second item on my list.
I need everyone on the team to submit weekly updates,
so I need to make that task stand out.
So I'll go to the formatting ribbon,
select bold, then select change font color, and choose blue.
Now, I'll type in a task for everyone.
Now, my text really stands out.
My post looks good.
To send it to the team,
I'll select Send and off it goes.
Formatting a post is a really simple way
to make what you have to say really stand out.
Now you can make your messages do more for you.