- [Instructor] Sharing information
is key to business success.
Your team members may come to your site
to learn or to help build the next idea.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you
how to share your SharePoint site
with stakeholders.
In this example, I'm responsible for organizing
a skills conference for my team.
I have a team site for presenters
working on the conference to collaborate.
I also have a communication site
to share information about the skills conference
with everyone at my company.
I want to share the team site,
and communication site with the right people.
From the start page,
I want to go to my skills conference presenters
team site.
I'll select members,
and the details of my group membership
appear in a window.
From here I can change permissions,
and add new members to this site.
I can also remove members,
and owners from this group.
Now I'll show you how to change permissions
on a communication site.
I'll navigate to the skills conference page.
To manage permissions,
I'll select share from the upper-right corner.
I'm the only owner,
and there are no members and no visitors
on this site.
Owners have full control of the site.
Members can view and edit,
and visitors can only view the site.
From this window,
I can also add users or groups
to share this site.
I want to share the site
with everyone except external users.
So I'll type in everyone,
and select everyone except external users.
Now I'll select share,
and I'll check the permissions again.
When sharing with everyone except external users,
by default, SharePoint only gives view access
or read permissions.
If needed,
I could change those permissions
by selecting the dropdown button under name.
I'll close share site now.
I have successfully shared my communication site,
and made sure people had the appropriate access.
Now you can share any site you create
with the appropriate people.
You can collaborate with a team
or create an engaging site
to get people excited about an upcoming event.