- [Instructor] If you often email the same group of people,
for example, your team at work,
instead of having to create an email and adding each person
as a recipient individually each time,
you can create a contact group,
so you'll only need to type the group's name,
to email everyone in that group.
To do this in Microsoft Outlook,
start by going to your contacts
by clicking the People button here in the navigation bar
and with the Home tab selected,
click the arrow next to New Contact
and choose Contact Group.
In this window that opens, enter a name for the group.
I'll call this staff instructors
to include everyone on my team,
then click Add Members.
From here you can choose to add existing contacts,
you have an Outlook from your address book,
or you can choose New Email Contact
to manually enter contact information.
For this example, I'll choose From Outlook Contacts.
And from here, I can double kick the names of the people
in my contacts that I want to add to this group.
Once I'm done there, I can click Okay.
You can say they've been added here
and I can click Save and Close.
So now anytime I want to send an email
to all three of those contacts,
I can just create a new email
and in the To field, start typing staff instructors,
select it, and this email will be sent
to everyone in this group.