- The internet offers a multitude of ways to communicate
and stay in touch with others.
This includes services like email, instant messaging,
website discussion boards, social media,
and even voice and video calls.
On top of learning how to use these various methods
of communication, it's also important
to understand when to use them.
For example, if you need to ask a coworker
a question that requires a time sensitive reply,
email might not be the best choice
as not everyone checks their email regularly
throughout the day.
Instead, your company may use an instant messaging service,
like Skype or Google Hangouts or Slack,
and sending a text-based message through that service
may get you a quicker reply.
In situations where you can wait a reasonable amount of time
for a reply, email is a better choice
as the general expectation is that email
is not for back and forth conversation in real-time,
but instead lets each person be a little more thoughtful
about their words and the information they're sharing.
Email is also useful to have a written record
of your conversations.
And of course, for real-time conversations,
when you can't be in the same room,
you have the option of traditional phone calls
or even video-based calls,
so you can both see and hear people in real-time.
Video calls can make it a little easier to communicate
effectively because they allow you to see the expressions
on the attendees faces during the call.
So again, understanding when to use certain types
of services is an important aspect of communicating online.