- [Instructor] To be able to easily communicate
with the people you message and call the most through Skype,
you'll need to add them as contacts.
By adding someone as a contact,
you can quickly see whether they're currently online.
And if so, you can get in touch with them
through text messages or calls with just a couple of clicks.
To add a contact, click in the search bar
and start typing the person's name.
(keyboard clacking)
If they have a Skype account, they should show up
in the list of results here in the Skype directory.
Once you've located them, you can right click their name
and choose to add them as a contact.
Now, if I clear the search,
you can see with contacts selected,
Oliver has been added to my contacts.
Now you can also search for people by their usernames,
which can be useful if the person you're searching for
has a common name, in which case,
you might see multiple results
when you search for them by name.
In those cases, you might want to ask your friend or colleague
what their Skype username is.
Then you can just type that username into the search field.
(keys clacking)
And then you can add them as a contact when they show up.
So that's how to add contacts to your Skype account.