- [Instructor] On your computer, your web browser
is the software you need in order to access
and interact with the content on the web.
Most operating systems come with at least one
built in web browser application.
For example, Mac OS computers include the Safari browser
and Windows 10 includes Microsoft Edge
but there are several other browsers
on the market to choose from including Google Chrome
and Mozilla Firefox.
At the most basic level, all browsers allow you to access
websites, download files, images, and videos
on websites and so on.
Browsers mainly vary in the features they include
but these days most browsers have very similar features.
Here we'll take a look at browsing the web
with Microsoft Edge, but you'll be able to use
other modern browsers in mostly the same away.
I'll open up Microsoft Edge and there it is.
To access a website, we enter the URL or address
of the site into the address bar at the top of the window.
The browser loads the webpage and it's displayed
in the main part of the window.
We can use the scroll bar to scroll down the page
to view it and to interact with all the elements
on the page.
White pages usually contain hyperlinks,
often just called links, that point to other pages
on the website or to entirely different websites.
You can often tell if text is a hyperlink
by its appearance.
It's usually a different color from the surrounding text
like we see here, or it becomes underlined or already
is underlined, or it's just visually different
in some other way.
Alternately, if you place your mouse over text
or an image and the cursor turns into a hand
with a pointing finger, that indicates
the item is a clickable link.
You'll also see the address that clicking the link
will take you to there in the lower left hand corner
and if I click that link I'll go to that page.
And now we're looking at the webpage that was linked
from the previous page and we can start browsing this page.
If necessary, you can go back to the previous page
by clicking the back button in the browser.
Similarly, you can click the forward button
to view that link page again.
Although it's easy to move back and forth
between pages like this, there are often times
when you need to reference multiple webpages
at the same time and going back and forth can get tedious.
A solution is to use tabs which are a feature
of web browsers which allow you to open multiple
webpages at the same time in the same browser window.
For example, maybe I'm searching for Microsoft Surface
tablets, I'll click that link, and as you can see
there are many different models to choose from here.
Clicking one of these takes me to the page
about that model and then I need to click the back button
to go back to the links to look at the other models.
To save time, I'm going to right click on the link
and choose open link in new tab.
In this particular browser, that opens a new tab
here in the background and you can see
the title of the page here.
In some web browsers, depending on your settings,
the new tab may open in the front, but in either case
you can switch back and forth between tabs
just by clicking on them.
So now I can right click on the links for the other
product versions I'm interested in
and open them in new tabs as well.
And once I've done that I can now switch among
all the tabs to do my research.
You can also open the web pages in new windows
by right clicking and choosing open link in new window.
Opening links in new windows can help you stay organized
by grouping related tabs in their own window
and opening unrelated tabs in other windows,
but that's a matter of personal preference.
But because these are separate windows, I can move
this one slightly out of the way and still see
the other window here in the background
and I can switch to that if I needed to.
You can always keep track of the web pages you visit
by using the history feature of the browser.
In Edge, click the three dot button here
in the upper right hand corner
and roll your mouse over history
and from here I can choose manage history
to see a list of the web pages I visited,
organized by date.
You have the option to clear web pages from your history
whenever you like, which you can do by clicking
clear browsing data and here I can choose
to clear the browsing history from the last 24 hours,
the last hour, the last seven days, the last four weeks
and all of my browsing history.
I'll leave that as is for now though.
Again, you'll find all the features we've seen here
in Microsoft Edge in other browsers as well,
but they may be located in different places.
But once you familiarize yourself with your preferred
browser, you'll find these features make it easy
to browse the web.