- Digital calendar applications
are a great way to keep track of meetings
and tasks on your own or with the people you work with.
Unlike traditional paper calendars or date books,
digital calendar software makes it easy
to keep your schedule synced with other people,
so if you schedule, reschedule,
or cancel meetings or appointments,
everyone's calendar is updated to reflect that information.
There are lots of popular calendar apps
used across multiple platforms, including Google Calendar,
Apple Calendar, and Microsoft Outlook.
In this chapter, we'll be focusing on Outlook
because in addition to it being
a professional calendar application,
it's also a full fledged email application
and contact manager, so you can easily keep
your appointments and other tasks synced between
yourself and others in one place.