- [Instructor] Microsoft Word's ability
to track changes allows you to freely make edits
to a document and your collaborators will be able to see
exactly what changes you made.
Start by going to the Review tab
and here click Track Changes.
With that enabled, Word will track any changes
you or anyone else makes to the document.
So for example, I might highlight some text here
and make that bold.
I see a misspelling down here, which I'll fix,
changing that A to an O.
And maybe down here I will create a new paragraph.
To review changes made to the document,
you can come back to the Review tab
and notice here we have this menu
that's currently set to Simple Markup.
We have several options here.
The Simple Markup option indicates
where changes have been made with a red line in the margin.
So you might've noticed that as I made my changes,
these red lines appeared.
All Markup shows the edits with a blue highlight,
and you can actually see the changes here in the document.
Now, in this first case at the top,
you can see that the change
is that the font was changed to bold.
Down here you can see that the A was deleted
and the O was typed in its place.
And here we can see another line
indicating a paragraph break.
There's also the option here of No Markup,
which hides all the markups
and shows you what the changes will look like
in the document.
And Original shows the document in its original form
without the changes,
which can be useful for comparing the original
with the edited version.
Additionally, when you're viewing an option
that displays the markups,
you can use the Show Markup menu here
to specify which types of revisions you want to see.
So for example,
if you only wanted to see formatting changes,
you could uncheck everything but that option.
And now you can see, I'm only seeing the change here,
where I changed this text to bold,
but if I want to see the other changes
I can add Insert and Deletions back,
and if I have comments, I can see those as well.
So, that's how to track changes to documents in Word.