- [Narrator] There are a lot of positive things
we can do online.
We can talk to friends and family,
we can make purchases and conduct business
all from behind our computers or mobile devices.
But online interactions aren't always safe.
There are always inherent risks in being active online,
so it's important to be aware
of the common scams that are out there.
One such scam is phishing.
Your personal information is a valuable asset
to people who want to steal it in order to sell it to others
or to impersonate you online
in order to access your various accounts.
Much like a common method for catching fish is
to put bait on a hook so the fish will want to eat it,
phishers have many different types of bait they use
to try to fool people into sharing information
like their passwords, credit card information,
and other private data.
They may send you an email or an instant message
through a social media site
or an online game you're playing.
They may pretend to be someone else
or make it look like they're an employee of a site you use
like a bank or your internet service provider
and ask you to click links to complete a task
under the guise of protecting your information
or making you think you're in some kind of trouble.
If you click their links or give them information,
they've hooked you like a fish.
So let's take a look at four practices
you can follow to avoid being hooked by these scammers.
First, be cautious of suspicious messages.
Scammers try to make their messages look official
and familiar to make you trust them,
often asking for you to confirm personal information
or account passwords.
Examine messages carefully
and avoid sharing information over messages or email.
If you receive a message claiming to be
from a company you've shopped
with in the past asking you to reply
with a password or other information, don't do it.
Instead, go to that company's website directly
from your browser and log into your account.
If they really need information from you,
you'll most likely see a message when you log in.
Alternately, call the company's
customer service line yourself.
Second, look for signs that a webpage is safe and secure.
Before you provide credit card information
or enter a password or other personal info,
take a look at the address bar in your browser
and make sure you either see a lock icon
or that the web address starts with HTTPS, not just HTTP.
The lock and HTTPS indicate
that the site is secure and encrypted,
so it's highly unlikely your information can be intercepted.
On top of that, make sure you're on the right webpage.
Scammers sometimes set up websites with addresses
very close to legitimate sites
and even design their scam sites
to look like those legitimate sites.
Oftentimes they'll misspell the company's name
or use a different domain address.
For example, they might have registered a dot net version
of a company's dot com address.
Always check the address to make sure you're
on the right page.
Third, keep your web browser
and operating system up-to-date.
You can turn on automatic updates
to make sure the latest software releases
are automatically installed on your computer,
which means you'll always receive
the latest security updates that help protect your computer.
And fourth, consider installing anti-malware software
on your computer.
This is special software designed to protect your computer
from malicious software and hackers.
Sometimes scammers trick people
into installing what looks like legitimate software,
but turns out to be software that tracks and steals data.
Anti-malware software can identify these malicious programs
and delete them from your computer.
Again, with all of its benefits,
there are still always risks to being online.
So you'll always want to stay vigilant and cautious
to protect yourself from phishing scams.