- [Presenter] The internet allows us to communicate
with other people in lots of different ways.
However, it isn't always safe
to communicate with other people online.
You don't always know for sure who you're talking to
when you're on the internet,
and every day online predators
pretend to be people they aren't.
Here are some tips you can use to keep yourself safer
when communicating online.
First, listen to your instincts.
If someone makes you feel nervous or uncomfortable
by asking probing questions
or trying to get information out of you,
stop communicating with them right away.
Most websites and social media sites have tools
that you can use to report suspicious activity.
Second, limit what you share.
Online predators often try to get you
to share personal information through emails
or other messaging services.
Just like you wouldn't share personal information
with a stranger on the street,
don't share information with strangers online, either.
And third, keep your distance.
Think twice about meeting someone in person
that you have only talked to online.
Online predators often use social media
to pretend to be someone else
by setting up fake profiles using other people's pictures.
Even if someone seems friendly,
it can be difficult to know for sure who they really are
when you're just talking online.
Always tell someone you trust
when an online stranger asks to meet you in person,
so you don't end up in a dangerous situation.
Keep these risks and tips in mind so you can stay safe
when you talk to people online.