- [Instructor] There are several types of media
that many of us come across on a daily basis.
These include traditional media like newspapers, magazines,
books, TV, and radio,
but also relatively newer forms of media,
like email, web articles, social media posts,
and a lot more.
We're constantly being inundated by media
that wants our attention.
It's easy to become overwhelmed by the flow of information,
if we don't develop the skills to navigate our way
through the ocean of information that surrounds us everyday
and learn to evaluate information with a critical eye.
Each year companies spend large sums of money
on internet advertising,
to the point where the line between information
and advertisements becomes blurred.
Other media can be filled with the attitudes
and opinions of others,
while other forms of media hide their message
under the surface of what we see and hear.
So it's important to develop media literacy
in order to avoid just passively accepting all messages
and instead learn to think carefully and critically
about the media we consume.
Here are five basic questions you can ask
when you encounter new information
and once you determine its accuracy and reliability.
Question one, who created the message?
Knowing who created the message,
may give you some insight in their purposes for doing so.
Was it to sell you something, to promote something
or was it to genuinely share information?
It's difficult to have a completely unbiased perspective,
but it's important to determine if the bias outweighs
or influences the information
and asking who created the message
can help give you the distance to see the information
being presented more clearly.
Question two, what techniques are being used
to capture your attention?
Is information being presented in a colorful video
with happy music?
Is it being delivered in ominous tones
with sensationalist phrasing?
The way the message is being presented
can have a big influence
on how you perceive that information.
Question three, how might different people
interpret this message?
We all consume information a little differently,
and it's important to step outside our own perspective
to explore multiple viewpoints.
Some information you come across may not take into account
the perspective and experience of others.
Question four is what's being left out of the message?
What points of view lifestyles or values
are being expressed in or alternately left out
of the message?
When making a message,
the author makes choices about what to keep in
and what to leave out.
And these choices
can reflect the author's values and attitudes.
Are certain perspectives being deliberately left out
of the message to influence your opinion?
And question five, why is this message being sent?
The purpose of this question is to examine the motivation
of sending the message in the first place.
It goes beyond the idea
that media is just there to entertain and inform
and asks who benefits from this message?
These five questions are not the only questions
you can and should ask when evaluating media,
but they can provide the necessary foundation
to start thinking critically
about the media we engage with every day.