- [Instructor] The World Wide Web,
also known as the web for short,
is a system that allows us to find information,
publish content, and get things done using the internet.
The documents on the web are called web pages,
which usually display information
and provide clickable links to other related web pages.
Web pages have gotten more and more interactive and robust,
and they exist for a wide variety of uses.
You can visit shopping websites to purchase goods online,
airline websites to book flights,
or the social media pages of your friends and relatives
to keep up with what they're doing.
Every webpage has an address on the internet called a URL,
which stands for a uniform resource locator.
To view a webpage, you type its URL into a software tool
called a web browser.
Typing an address into a web browser
is similar to dialing a phone number on a phone.
Just like how dialing a phone number connects you
to a specific phone, typing a URL connects you
to the location that webpage is stored, called a web server,
which loads the web pages onto our screens,
so we can read and interact with them.
So by using the web,
we can access almost any type of information
from anywhere with an internet connection.