- To access information and to communicate
with others online, you first need to connect
to the internet.
This is also known as getting online.
To do this you need an internet capable device
to connect to a network.
These devices include desktop and laptop computers,
mobile phones and tablets.
Nearly all modern devices in these categories
have the ability to connect to networks to get online.
Essentially, the internet is made up of a set of networks
that are connected to each other all across the world
and you get online and on the internet
by connecting to one of these networks.
Oftentimes you'll be connecting to a network
that's been set up in your home or place of work.
Depending on the device you're using,
you can connect the networks in different ways.
For example, if you're using a desktop computer,
you may have a wired connection to your network
for internet access.
Many laptop computers also have ports
to support a wired connection as well.
For a wired connection, you'll use a cable
called an ethernet cable to connect your computer
to your network device, often called a router.
Most laptop computers also have the ability to connect
to wifi networks, which is a wireless form of connection,
so you can choose between a wired and wireless connection
from most laptops.
When using portable devices like mobile phones and tablets,
you'll also typically connect to your network via wifi.
If your mobile phone or tablet has a data plan
through your mobile provider, you can also connect
to the internet wirelessly over cellular signals
when wifi isn't available.
This is referred to as mobile broadband.
When you're on the go though, connecting to wifi networks
is generally the best option as many mobile providers
limit the amount of data you can transfer
over mobile broadband and may charge extra fees
for going over your limit.
Publicly available wifi networks are also available
in places like airports, hotels,
shopping centers, and restaurants.
Oftentimes public wifi networks are password protected,
which is a method for securing the network
from being accessed by just anyone.
For example, a coffee shop may decide to only share
the password to their wifi network with customers.
Similarly, the wifi network you may have set up in your home
should also be password protected to prevent people
from outside your household from connecting to it.
Home networks are usually set up
by your internet service provider or ISP.
Your ISP sets you up with a modem
for creating the connection from your home to the internet
and often the service includes a router
which allows multiple computers and devices
to connect to the internet at the same time,
either wired or wirelessly.
For the most part, getting online is quick and easy
as long as you have an available network to connect to.