- [Instructor] When working on a document with your team,
you don't have to call a meeting every time
you need to share notes or comments with each other.
With Microsoft Word, you and your team members
can add comments directly to the document
for everyone to see and review.
This allows everyone to share feedback
and collaborate in one place, the document itself.
To make a comment, place your cursor at the location
in the document where you want the comment to appear.
For example, I'll place my cursor
next to this logo at the top of the page.
Then I'll go to the Review tab of the ribbon.
And from here, I'll click New Comment.
You can see it draws a line from where my cursor was
over here to the side, and I can type my comment.
So it's that easy.
You can also highlight specific words or phrases
to apply your comments to so it's clear
what you're commenting on.
For example, I noticed that the name of the hotel founder
is misspelled a few times in this document.
So I'll highlight one of those misspellings,
and this time, I'll right-click on that
and choose New Comment.
And now I can type my comment just like before.
You can also read and respond to comments left by others.
If I scroll down a bit,
notice here we have a comment left by Jake.
When I roll over it, I can click Reply
and start a conversation thread on this particular comment.
You can also click Resolve when an issue has been addressed.
That grays out the comment
so others can see that it's been handled.
But they can still read and review the comment thread
if they need to.
If you want to remove a comment entirely
from the document, you can use the Delete button
here in the Review tab.
If you want to hide comments from view
without deleting them,
toggle them with the Show Comments button.
You can see that hides all of my comments,
and now I just see these little comment icons
indicating where they are in the document.
I can click on them to read them.
And if I want to see them again,
I can just click Show Comments.
So as you can see,
comments are a useful tool for collaborating
and sharing feedback on a document with others.