- [Instructor] While many online communication services
allow you to make audio and video calls to other people,
in most cases, the people you're calling
need to be using the same service.
For example, in the popular WhatsApp communication tool,
you can call other WhatsApp users,
but only call other WhatsApp users.
Skype, on the other hand,
is one of the few communication tools
where in addition to you texting and calling
other Skype users, you can also call actual phone numbers.
So from Skype, you can call your friends and family,
the store down the street or in another state,
or any business or person who may not have Skype,
but who does have a phone number.
Now, while calls between Skype users are free,
calls from Skype to phone numbers require you to purchase
a Skype credit or a Skype subscription.
You can find the rates for your country
by going to skype.com,
and here clicking Skype to phone.
Then select your country,
and here you'll see the rates
for Skype credits and subscriptions.
If you just want to try out calling phones
from Skype, though,
you can make a call up to five minutes in length for free.
Just sign into Skype and click the dial pad button.
Then enter the phone number you want to call.
And notice it says here I can talk
for five minutes for free.
I'll click the call button.
- [Operator] Hi, you've reached the National Weather Service
in Oxnard, California.
For a recording of the current weather forecast, press one.
- [Instructor] And we'll just hang up on that for now.
But that's how easy it is to call a phone number from Skype.
Again, if this is something you think you'll frequently do,
be sure to look into purchasing Skype credits
or a subscription.