- The internet makes it possible for us to stay in touch
with our friends, family, and colleagues online.
Communication can happen in real-time
with apps and services that make it easy
to chat through instant messaging,
voice calling and video calls.
Instant messaging is a text-based form of communication,
where you can type messages on your computer
or mobile device to send to people
who can then instantly read and respond to your messages
on their devices.
Voice calling over the internet
is similar to traditional phone calls,
only instead of using a landline or mobile phone,
you place your call over the internet using an app.
And video calling is like a voice call,
but where you and the people you're calling
can hear and see each other.
Which of these three forms of communication you use
depends on what you determine is appropriate at the time.
If you just need to ask a quick question,
but don't necessarily need an immediate response,
you can send an instant message.
Your recipients can then respond when they have a moment.
If you need a more immediate reply,
you can try a voice call.
And video-based calls can make it easier
to have certain conversations because you can see each other
and read the expressions on each caller's face.
In many cases, there are apps that allow you to use
all three of these forms of communication
while other apps focus specifically on one or two types.
Apple FaceTime, for example,
allows you to make voice and video calls,
but you use a separate Apple app called iMessage
for instant messaging.
Another example is WhatsApp,
which is an app that lets you send messages
and voice and video chat as well.
And there's also Skype,
which in addition to instant messages
and voice and video chatting is also one of the few apps
through which you can call phone numbers,
letting you make both domestic and international calls
from your computer or mobile phone.
In this chapter, we'll look more closely
at communicating using Skype.