- [Instructor] In the OneDrive web interface,
there are three main areas for helping you
view, work with, and manage your files.
We have the navigation pane over here on the left,
the toolbar across the top,
and the file list, which takes up
the majority of the window.
You may see slightly different views
depending if you're signed into OneDrive
with a personal, work, or student account,
but basically, you click any of the categories here
in the navigation pane to determine
what you see in the file list area.
Currently, I have My files selected,
so I'm looking at all of my files.
I can click Recent to see the files
I've worked with the most recently,
Photos to see the photo stored on my OneDrive account,
and so on.
Up here in the toolbar area,
you can use the search field to search
for files on your OneDrive,
as well as create new folders or documents,
or upload files from your computer to OneDrive.
You can also sort files to make it easier
to locate the ones you want to work with.
For example, I may want to sort
by the most recently modified files.
And you can change the view
of your files from this menu here.
I can try a compact list, tiles, or photos.
To work with a file, select it in the file list area,
and then, choose what you'd like
to do with it in the toolbar area.
We can open it, share it, download it, delete it, and so on.
The toolbar also lets you check information
about your selected file by clicking this info button.
For example, if it's a file you have shared with
or are collaborating on with others,
you can see who has access to the file
and who last worked on it.
So that's an overview of how to manage
your files in OneDrive.