- [Narrator] The internet and social media platforms
allow us to connect with our friends, family,
and peers in a variety of ways.
It's a great way to keep in touch,
but sometimes people take advantage of these platforms
and use them to spread negative messages about others.
Cyberbullying or bullying that takes place on the internet
can be just as bad as bullying in person.
People can use the internet to send hurtful messages
to someone, spread fake rumors
or share someone's private information without permission.
The results of cyberbullying can be just as impacting
as face to face bullying.
When someone is cyberbullied,
their feelings can be hurt
and their reputation can be damaged.
You can't always prevent cyberbullying,
but you can play a part in making the internet a friendlier
and safer place for everyone.
Here's some guidelines you can follow
to promote civility online.
First, simply avoid sending negative messages
and participating in behavior that can hurt someone else.
Respect differences.
When you interact with people online,
respect their differences in opinion, experience
and culture.
Even if you don't agree with something
that another person shares online,
you should still treat them with respect
and make the internet a friendly place
for communication and discussion.
Think about the consequences of sharing.
Before you share or post anything online,
always pause and think about the consequences of doing so.
Will your message hurts someone else?
Will it damage your reputation or the safety
or reputation of others?
Does it contribute anything constructive
to the conversation?
If you feel unsafe online,
you should feel comfortable to remove yourself
from a situation and report it to someone you trust.
There is no rule requiring you to engage in conversations
or arguments with people online.
And when you do see cruel or dangerous activity online,
offer to support those involved
and report the incident to someone you trust.
We can all play a part in being responsible,
digital citizens online in making the internet a safe
and friendly place for everyone.