- Thanks to the internet
we can store information online from one device
and access it from another device almost instantly.
This is commonly referred to
as storing information in the cloud.
The cloud is basically a collection of software services
that are running in multiple locations on the internet
instead of running on a single user's computer.
That means that storing content in the cloud,
makes it easy to access your information from any device
in any location where you have internet access.
Some cloud-based services you might've heard of
include Dropbox, Apple's iCloud drive,
Google Drive, and Microsoft OneDrive.
So for example, instead of saving your important documents
and other files to your computer,
you can save them to OneDrive,
which will allow you to get to them from anywhere.
This means that if you're working on a file
on your home computer and save it to OneDrive,
and later you're on the road with only your mobile phone,
you can still access and download that file
through OneDrive on your phone.
In this chapter, we'll take a look at how to save
and access files from OneDrive,
but you'll find that the process of doing so
is very similar to working with other cloud-based services.