- [Instructor] OneDrive is a useful resource
for storing files that you want to share
or distribute to others.
Even with the default amount of storage space
you get with a free OneDrive account,
you can share much larger files than you could
by sending them over e-mail.
Sharing a file with others from OneDrive
is a simple matter of generating a link
that you can send to them.
Start by selecting the file you want to share
from your file list,
then in the toolbar, click the Share button.
In this Send link area that opens,
you can enter the e-mail addresses
of the people you want to share the file with,
to have Microsoft automatically send an e-mail
with a link to that file when you click Send.
Alternately, you can generate a link by clicking Copy Link,
and that creates a link you can copy it to your clipboard
by clicking Copy.
And then you're free to paste that address
into an e-mail you're composing yourself
or into an instant messaging program
or a webpage you're publishing, and so on.
For example, I've already started composing
an e-mail message in Microsoft Outlook,
and here I'll just right click and choose Paste
to paste in that address.
And once I'm done, I can click Send
to send the e-mail containing this link,
and my recipient will be able to click that link
to download the file to her own computer.
So that's a look at how easy it is
to share files from OneDrive.