- [Instructor] If you use the internet,
you should be aware of your digital footprint.
Just like physical footprints on a dirt path
that show where someone has been walking,
your digital footprint is the history
of all of your online activity.
Any social media posts you make, any websites you visit,
and any information you share online
contributes to your digital footprint.
Now, your digital footprint isn't a single item,
it's more of the impression and profile
that people can build about you
by viewing and following what you've done online
across various websites and other online services.
The thing to keep in mind
is that once you post something online,
you have no guarantee that it can be erased.
If you post something on social media
and then delete it from your account,
other people may have already seen it,
or they might have taken a screenshot of it.
So the posts and activity
that contribute to your digital footprint can last forever.
Now, this can be a good thing if your digital footprint
includes things that give you a positive reputation online
and help you build your personal brand.
Your online history can also help the apps you use
to know more about you.
They can use this information to serve you better
by adjusting to the things you like and your daily habits.
But they can also use this information in the wrong way
and share it with others.
Keep the following tips in mind when you go online
to manage your digital footprint.
First, know what your footprint says about you.
People who search for you online
will make judgements about you based on what they find.
This can include employers when you apply for a job,
or recruiters when you apply for academic programs.
It's important to know
what your digital footprint says about you
and how your information is being used.
To see what your personal brand is online,
you can search for yourself.
Search for your name in a search engine
and see what results are displayed.
If these results don't show you what you want,
think about what you share online
and what information you allow other people to see.
Secondly, actively manage your privacy settings.
You can modify the privacy settings
of most of the social media sites
and online applications you use.
This can help you control who sees what you share
and what information shows up
when someone searches for you online.
Third, manage your cookies.
Cookies are notes given to your web browser
as you browse the web.
These cookies help apps track information that they need
while you're using the app.
This can help the app work better for you.
But this data also contributes to your digital footprint
as it allows other sites to gain information
about the sites you visit and your interests.
You can use the settings in your web browser
to limit or block the use of cookies on certain websites.
And fourth, think before you share.
Behave like once you share something online,
you can't take it back, because that's often the case.
Make sure you're okay with something
being part of your public persona before you share it
because your digital footprint can live indefinitely online.
So keep these tips in mind to make sure you're happy
with your digital footprint and how it's used.