- [Instructor] When you upload files to OneDrive,
you can securely access, update and share them
from anywhere you have an internet connection.
There's several ways to upload files to OneDrive.
Let's take a look at a few of the methods here.
After signing in to your account,
just click the Upload button in the toolbar,
choose to upload files,
and then browse for and select the files you want
to copy to OneDrive.
In this case, I want to upload all three of these,
so I'll just select all three and click Open,
and there are the files.
You can also drag files from your computer directly
into the OneDrive browser window.
I'll make the browser window a little bit smaller
so I can see my desktop where I have some folders of files.
And again, I can just select the files I want to upload.
And in this case, I will drag them into the browser window.
You can see they're uploading and there they are.
If you're using the Google Chrome or Microsoft Edge browser,
you can upload folders of files instead of individual files.
This can make it easier to keep your files organized.
Just click the Upload button again,
and this time choose a Folder
and then select the folder you want to upload.
I'll confirm that I want to upload the entire folder
and here's that folder.
Now, if you're using a browser other than Chrome or Edge,
you can create a new folder first
by clicking the New menu and choosing Folder,
giving it a name, and then you can upload
or drag files into that folder you just created.
I'll click the folder to go into it
and then I move my window out of the way.
I'll select my files and I'll drag them
into the OneDrive window,
and there they are.
And once you've uploaded your files to OneDrive,
you can get to them from any computer, tablet
or mobile phone with an internet connection.