- [Instructor] These days, buying products
and services online is pretty easy in most cases
but it can be a little tricky or even scary
if you haven't done it before or very often.
There are lots of reasons to make online purchases.
You might be physically far away from a credible seller
of something you want or maybe you just want to be able
to browse a variety of stores at the same time
to find the best options or prices.
Whatever the reason, online shopping allows you to make
your decisions and purchases quickly and easily
from your computer.
Before going on a website to make a purchase,
it's generally a good idea to know what product
you're looking for and where you might purchase it
because there are many platforms and sellers
to purchase from online.
It can help to do some online research to find content
that can help you decide where to purchase the product
you're looking for.
You can do this by typing the product's name
into the browser search bar, followed by the word review.
So for example, maybe I'm interested in finding out
about the Microsoft Surface tablet.
So I could type Surface tablet review.
This can lead you to reviews that are written by others
who have purchased the product or service you're looking for
as well as reviews written by professional
and trusted sources.
Combined, these reviews can help you decide if a product
or service is reliable and a good fit for your needs.
Once you've determined the product you want to buy
and identified a reliable seller,
it's time to make the purchase.
Many e-commerce websites make it easy to browse products
using categories or to search for specific products
using a search bar or to compare similar items.
If the product you're looking for has available options
like different configurations, colors, or features,
you'll find links to manage your preferences.
When you're ready to purchase a product,
look for a button that's usually labeled buy now
or add to cart or something similar.
Just like a physical cart at a physical store,
an online shopping cart keeps tracks of products
you intend to buy from that site.
So for example, maybe I decided I also
want to purchase this mouse.
I'll click add to cart.
And if I scroll back up, you can see I now have two items
in my cart.
You'll always have the chance to add or remove items
from your cart before you make your purchase.
So if I change my mind, I can just click remove.
And that takes it out of the cart.
Once you've added the products you want,
you're ready to check out.
Depending on the shopping website you're using,
you may be required to create an account
before completing your purchase.
As always, be cautious when sharing your information
to create an account.
Never share personal information other than the shipping
and billing information required to make your purchase.
And look in the address bar of the website
for this lock icon.
That indicates that the site is encrypted and secure.
This means that only the company will be able to view
the information you're sending.
If you don't see any indication of site security,
don't enter any information and consider making
your purchase on a different website
that carries the same products.
Additionally, it's not a good idea to make purchases
while using a public Wi-Fi network.
If possible, wait until you're on your home network
to make your purchases.
If you have an account with the website you're using,
you can still browse the site while on a public network.
And the items you add to your cart will often remain there
when you log into your site again from home
to complete your purchase.
And after completing your purchase, which involves
entering your name, email address, shipping information,
and payment info like your credit card number,
you should receive an email confirming your purchase.
Many sites let you then track your order so you can monitor
its progress to your location.
So that's the basic rundown of making online purchases.
When done properly, it can be a convenient way to research
and buy products from your computer.