- [Instructor] You can use Outlook to keep track
of your personal appointments
as well as schedule meetings with other people.
In Outlook, switch to the calendar view
by clicking this icon in the navigation area
at the bottom of the window.
I'm currently viewing my calendar by the month,
but you can click the options in the ribbon
under the Home tab to also be your calendar by day,
the workweek, or the entire week as well.
I'll switch back to the month view for now.
Start by selecting the date of the appointment
or meeting you want to add to your calendar.
Then, you can click New Appointment or New Meeting.
The difference between an appointment
and a meeting is that you can invite others to meetings
and appointments are generally events
you'll attend on your own or without inviting others.
I'll choose New Appointment.
Here, enter the title of your appointment,
and because we selected the date first,
it should already be filled out correctly
in the start time area,
but you can change it here if necessary.
Then, select the time of the appointment
and then, enter the end time
to block off that time on your calendar.
You can also select All day to designate
the appointment as an all day event,
rather than taking place at a specific time.
I'll uncheck that for now, and then, click Save & Close.
And now, that appointment is on my calendar.
Adding a meeting is very similar.
Just click the date of the meeting
and then, click New Meeting.
Again, enter a title.
In the Required area, you'll add the names of people
who are required to attend this meeting.
If you've previously created a contact group,
you can type the group's name here.
You can also enter the contact info for people
for whom the meeting is optional.
If necessary, you can add other details like the location.
Then, click Send.
That adds the appointment to your calendar
and also emails the meeting invite
and details to the contacts you added.
So that's how to set up appointments
and meetings in Outlook.