- [Instructor] A big part of staying safe
and keeping your information private online
is protecting your information,
your accounts, and your computer, by using strong passwords.
A strong password is like a strong lock for your home.
You want a lock that is hard to break,
and you don't want anyone else finding the key to your lock.
Here's some tips for creating a strong password.
Use a combination of letters, numbers,
and symbols in your password.
Using a combination of uppercase and lowercase letters
and characters and adding numbers can improve the strength
of your password.
Avoid using common words in your password.
This includes common words
and phrases like password or website,
as well as personal keywords
that might be easily guessed like your birthday,
your name, or your hometown.
Hackers can easily guess
or research these phrases in your password.
So a unique combination of characters
and numbers creates a stronger password.
For example, let's say I wanted
to use the word penguin as my password.
That's way too common a word.
So one trick is to think of ways
to obscure the word you want to use,
but still make sure you can remember it
when it's time to enter your password.
Let's say that the year 1972 is personally important to me,
but it's not an obvious year like my birth year
that could be easily guessed by others.
So I might come up with a password like this,
where I placed penguin between the digits of the year
and capitalize two of its letters.
And then I add a symbol at the end
to make it that much more difficult to guess.
This is much safer
than just using the word penguin by itself,
and it's a password I can remember without writing down.
You can come up with your own strategy
for creating passwords with the methods similar to this.
Now, with that said,
don't use the same password for multiple sites.
Instead use different passwords for different accounts,
because if someone guesses your email password,
your safety and privacy may be in trouble
if you use the same password for your bank account.
Be sure to use different passwords
for each online account you have.
And your password is only for you.
When you share it with others, even friends and family,
it's more likely that someone else will use it
or won't keep it safe.
Keep your passwords to yourself.
When you log in to accounts, make sure you log out
when you're done and don't save your login information
on a public computer.
And as a general rule,
you should avoid doing personal business
on public computers and public networks
as this makes it easier for hackers
to access your information.
Remember, using strong passwords
and keeping them secure is important
for your online safety and privacy.
Keep these tips in mind when you create a new password.