- [Zakiya] In every changing world,
there are always new things to be learned.
As technology advances and new roles are in demand each day,
building on existing skills and learning new ones
is necessary to keep up.
You deserve all that comes with new opportunities
and you can do it.
My name is Zakiya Mackey and I've built my career
helping others build new skills, broaden their horizons,
and learn new tips for success.
In this course I'll cover some Microsoft 365 products
that will help in any tech based role.
I'll also help you use existing products
for maximum efficiency,
share best practices and industry standards,
as well as some pointers to optimize your workflow
in the workplace.
When you level up your workflow,
you can change your career trajectory
and become more successful.
I want you to be able to use Microsoft 365 tools
to stay organized, engage your audience,
and collaborate with others more effectively.
Let's get to it.