- [Instructor] Between new conversations, documents,
and messages, if you leave your inbox unorganized,
all the emails you receive can be difficult to sort through.
In this lesson I'm going to show you a few best practices
for organizing your email inbox in Outlook
so you can keep track
of the flow of information as it comes in.
One of the best ways to keep emails top of mind
is to add flags.
Flags are an easy way to label the importance of an email
that you aren't going to take immediate action on.
In this example, I'll flag the emails that are related
to the event that I'm managing.
So first I'm going to start
from the Microsoft 365 homepage and open Outlook.
Here I'm in my inbox.
There are new unread messages
as well as messages that I've already read.
To set a flag,
hover your cursor over the email message,
then select the flag icon in the top right corner
of the message.
The flag changes to red.
And when the email message is opened,
a followup message appears in the header of the email.
To remove the flag, select the flag icon.
The follow up flag changes to a check mark.
When the email is open,
in the top header it states the date the flag was complete.
Another way to keep emails organized
is to use color categories.
Color categories allow you to identify
and group associated items in Outlook
so you can quickly track and organize them.
Before using a color category you first need to create one.
Select the email you wish to add to a category,
navigate to the ribbon,
identify the categorize icon, select the dropdown menu,
and then new category.
Add a name for the category and select a color,
I'll name mine customer event.
Then select save.
This color category is now ready to use.
Next I'll right click a message from the message list,
select categorize, and select the category I just created
from the list.
You can even assign a color category from the reading pane
or an open message.
The next inbox organizing tool I recommend using
is auto reply.
Auto reply allows you to respond to emails
when you're out of office or unavailable.
To set up auto reply select the settings icon,
then view all Outlook settings.
And then automatic replies.
Turn on the automatic replies toggle
and then you can type your message in the message box.
Type in your out of office message.
I like to use something like, thank you for your email.
I am out of the office.
I will respond when I return.
If you don't want your out of office message
sent all the time, select send replies during a time period.
Then choose the dates and times
you'd like to set your automatic reply for.
You can also select
if you want Outlook to block your calendar
for that time period, decline new invites,
or cancel any meetings you might have during this period.
You can format the text using the toolbar
or cut and paste text you've already formatted,
including hyperlinked text.
When you're finished
with the message and settings, select save.
Now Outlook is programmed to send the automated reply
as a response to messages during your selected times.
Sorting and organizing your email are key skills
for keeping important communications and information
easy to find.
An organized inbox will keep you focused
and allow you to spend your time on more important tasks.
Try using these tools to bring order
to your inbox this week and see how much time you can save.