- Calls are a great tool for team meetings and quick chats.
It's important to have the right settings
just in case you miss a call
In this lesson, I'll show you how to manage
your call settings on Teams.
To get started, I'll open Teams
from the Microsoft 365 homepage.
Next to your profile picture near the top,
select the three dots for more options.
Then select Settings.
Now, let's say you'll be out of the office
and you want to forward your incoming calls.
On the left menu, go to Calls
and under Call answering rules, choose Forward my calls
and Teams will forward all calls directly to your voicemail.
If you select Configure voicemail under Voicemail,
you will be able to record a greeting.
You can also select how you would like Teams
to handle calls when a caller goes to voicemail.
They can record a message,
choose to record a message
or be transferred to someone else,
end the call without playing your greeting,
play the greeting and end the call,
or just be transferred to someone else of your choosing.
If you select Transfer the call to someone else,
you will need to designate a person
for the call to be transferred to.
I'll select Isaiah.
When a caller calls you,
the call will be transferred to the designated person.
You can also specify the language for your greeting,
as well as customize a text-to-speech greeting option.
This option allows you to have a written greeting
and would replace your voicemail.
Should you want to create a custom
out of office text greeting,
place your cursor below where it says
Your custom out of office greeting
and write your out of office greeting.
I'll write I'm out of the office.
Feel free to send me an email.
Below it, you can select when your out of office
custom greeting will display.
Select OK to save your changes.
I encourage you to put the proper settings in place
to manage your calls so that you can make sure
all calls are answered according to your availability.
Give it a try.