- [Instructor] Depending on the audience
and your familiarity with the content,
creating a presentation can be a nerve-wracking experience.
Is this the right info?
Is that the right format to use?
Thankfully PowerPoint can take away some of these questions
and make presentation creation a breeze.
In this lesson, I'm going to share some best practices
so that you can become a better presenter
and deliver a clear message in every presentation you give.
To start I'm going to open a PowerPoint presentation.
You can follow along
with the sample presentation in your exercise files.
It's called customer event example A.
First consider what style and font to use.
You want to make sure
that your audience will be able to read from a distance.
I recommend using a font style that is not too decorative
in a size between 20 and 24 point.
To adjust the font and style size, I'll navigate
to the top ribbon and make sure home is selected.
From here I'll highlight the text in the slide
and select the font
and size from the dropdown menu in the home tab.
Next use bullet points
and short sentences to share your information.
A minimal amount of text on your slide is the way to go
to keep your audience engaged.
I recommend that each idea should fit on one line.
To emphasize points and help tell a story, use pictures,
graphics, charts, and graphs.
Be sure to add labels to help your audience
identify the purpose of the visual elements.
It's also important to keep backgrounds subtle and uniform.
Keeping your background colors subtle will help
your audience focus on the points in the presentation.
To edit your background
navigate to the design tab and select background.
A solid fill is usually the least distracting.
Next, use themes to set a high contrast
between the background color and the text color.
To change your theme
open your existing PowerPoint presentation,
navigate to design in the top ribbon,
and select a theme from the dropdown menu.
I also recommend
that you use the accessibility checker.
Navigate to the top ribbon, select review,
and then check accessibility.
PowerPoint will give you tips to address any errors
that might make it hard for anyone to view.
Next, use the presenter coach
to practice your presentation delivery.
To access the presenter coach
go to the slideshow tab in the top ribbon
and select rehearse with coach.
When your presentation appears,
you can practice your delivery by selecting start rehearsal.
After you finish the rehearsal report will give you
information like your pace, pronunciation, pitch,
and time spent to support you as you work
to perfect your presentation skills and style.
Next, use your notes.
Don't just read the text on the slides word for word.
Practice what you'll say about the key points
so you don't get confused or miss any relevant information
while you're presenting.
To add notes to your presentation
navigate to the view tab in the top ribbon and select notes.
Now go forth and practice your presentation.