- [Instructor] Having the skills to create great documents
puts you on the path to great results.
Adding structure and media to your documents
can help bring clarity to your work
and make it more organized.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you
how to incorporate formatting techniques
into your documents
so they are easy to navigate and understand.
I'll start from the Microsoft 365 homepage.
In this example, I'm going to enhance and invent itinerary
with some photos and formatting.
Follow along by downloading the sample word document
in your exercise files.
It's called Customer Event Itinerary Example (A).
To add a picture to a document,
I'll place my cursor where I want the image.
Navigate to the top ribbon in word and select insert,
then picture.
Then I'll need to choose the source of the image
from these options.
This device, one drive, stock images, and bing pictures.
I need to find a picture.
So I'm going to select stock images.
When the stock images window appears, use the search bar
to find the kind of picture you are looking for.
I'll type travel.
Once I find the photo, I'll select insert.
And it's added into the document where the cursor is placed.
To resize the photo, select it,
and navigate to the top ribbon under picture
for formatting options.
There are lots of editing options, photo size modifications,
border additions, photo enhancements,
and how text appears relative to the photo.
I can also resize the photo manually
by dragging the white dots on the sides
and corners of the photo.
Adding titles at the header or footer of your document
can be helpful with keeping related topics organized
and give your document a clear, easy to follow format.
The header is located in the top margin of your document,
and the footer is in the bottom margin.
To add titles to the header or footer of your document,
select insert on the top ribbon in Word,
then select header and footer.
From here, you can place the cursor
in the header or footer of the page
which is distinguished by shading out the body text
and you're ready to type directly into each.
I'm going to add my name to the header
and format it to appear on every page
by selecting same across entire document
under the options dropdown menu on the right.
So after you add your text,
you can choose how you want it formatted.
I'll make my name bold by highlighting the text
and selecting bold in the menu that appears above my cursor.
Next I'll select the shaded text
to return to the body of the document.
Now all the pages of my document have the same header.
To see this, go to view in the top ribbon
and select reading view.
To exit out of reading view,
navigate to the top ribbon and select edit document,
then edit in the dropdown menu.
I can also add page numbers to headers and footers.
I'll navigate to the top ribbon and select insert,
and then select page numbers.
This dropdown menu provides options for placement
of the page numbers.
I'll select add page number to the center of the footer
and Word adds the appropriate page numbers to each page.
To see this, go to view in the top ribbon
and select reading view.
To exit out of reading view,
navigate to the top ribbon and select edit document.
Then edit in the dropdown menu.
And when I no longer need page numbers,
I'll navigate to the top ribbon, select insert,
page numbers,
then select remove page numbers under the options.
Next, a page break creates separation within a document
and can be used to introduce a new idea
or start new chapters or pages.
To add a page break, place your cursor
where you want one page to begin and the other to end.
Next, navigate to insert and then select page break
for the page break to appear.
When printing the document,
the break doesn't visually appear.
To remove the page break,
double click the break you want to remove
and then press delete on your keyboard.
Adding pictures and formatting can significantly enhance
the information shared in your document.
Try formatting or adding pictures
to liven up your next document.