- [Instructor] And now we've reached the end of this course,
but it's not the end of your journey.
There will always be new things to learn
and new ways to build efficiency.
I want to leave you with some resources
that will help you along your way.
First, I recommend that you check out
the Microsoft Community page and join the conversation.
The Microsoft Community is a great place
to find quick tips and solutions
to typical issues that you encounter.
You can ask questions of the support team
as well as speak to other users just like you.
And lastly, explore the products and make mistakes.
It's only through making mistakes
that you can learn how to troubleshoot
and solve problems on your own.
I know that you have the ability and skill
to achieve anything you set your mind to.
Thanks for watching this course.
I wish you the best
as you learn new avenues for navigating your own success
and building the career that you want and deserve.
Good luck in all your future endeavors.