- [Instructor] Have you ever needed more than just words
to capture ideas correctly?
Having images or videos can be helpful
to reference along with notes.
In this lesson,
I'll show you how to insert media
and tables into OneNote
to create an interactive notebook in OneNote.
So first, I'll open OneNote
to an existing notebook of mine, customer event.
To add a picture,
place the cursor where you want to add it.
Select Insert from the top ribbon, then Picture,
and select From Online.
In the search bar,
type the name of an image you are looking for
and press Enter.
Use the scroll bar on the right side of the window
and select the picture that works best for you.
Select Insert when finished.
The picture will add and appear in your notes
where you placed it.
Let's say you want to reference another file
in your notes.
To attach a copy of a file to your notebook,
you'll place the cursor where you want to link the file.
Select Insert, then File.
Then Insert File Attachment.
Select the file you want, and then select Open.
You can also insert videos from the internet
into your notes.
Find the video you want online,
copy the video URL from the address bar,
and then select where you want it on the page
and paste it.
You can select the link to play the video back
on the original website,
or select the Play button on the embedded video
and watch it right in your notes.
When data needs to be stored and shared in a table,
you can create one directly in your notebook.
Adding tables in your notes can also be helpful
in keeping groups of information together
and sorted appropriately.
To add a table to your notes, select Insert, then Table.
Next, select how many rows and columns you need.
The amount selected will be highlighted.
When you work in a table,
the table menu becomes available in the ribbon.
You can also right click on the table
to have the menu appear.
Select Table to further customize your table,
like insert or delete rows or columns.
Sometimes words just don't do enough.
Adding files, videos,
and tables helps to add dimension
and further clarification to your notes.
Try adding some pictures or a table to your notes
to help you better explain and organize information.