- [Educator] Referring to specific resources in a document
can take up a lot of space.
With footnotes, you can keep your references organized
and easy to read.
In this lesson,
I'm going to show you how to reference your content in Word
with footnotes and adding a table of contents.
Footnotes are used to explain, comment on,
or provide references to something in a document.
A table of contents helps you to locate specific information
in a document.
To get started,
I'll open Word from the Microsoft 365 homepage.
You can follow along with the sample Word document
in your exercise files,
it's called Customer Event Product Document.
In this example, I'll be editing a product document
from a customer event I'm organizing.
First, I'll add footnotes.
Footnotes are citations that appear at the footer
or the bottom of the page.
Once a footnote has been added,
you'll have a small superscript number after the cited text
and the full citation on the page's footer.
To insert a footnote,
I'll place my cursor
to the right of the text I want to cite.
From here, I'll navigate to the top ribbon,
select References, and then Insert Footnote.
At this point, a window appears where I can specify
the details of the original work I'm citing.
I'll enter St. Clair Housen "To Be A Mogul"
Chapter 3, Page 46, Line 22.
This is the first footnote I'm adding to the document.
So the number one is in the box.
Press the Escape button on your keyboard,
or select the body of the document
to save and close the footnote.
When I'm in editing view,
I can't see the citation at the bottom of the page,
but the footnote will be there.
If I select the number, I can edit the footnote details.
To see how the footnote appears in your document,
I need to be in reading view.
Navigate to the top ribbon, select View,
then select Reading View.
Now, when I scroll through the document,
I can see that the footnotes are at the bottom of the page.
Now, I'll select the Edit Document tab in the top ribbon
and then choose Edit.
Word will send you back to editing view
where you can continue editing.
If a footnote is not the citation method you want to use,
consider an end note,
which adds the footer text to the end of the document
instead of the bottom of the page.
Navigate to the top ribbon, select References,
and then Insert End Note.
Another way to keep your document organized
is to add a table of contents.
Before you create a table of contents,
you need to select your texts and apply a heading.
Word uses the headings in your document
to build an automatic table of contents
that can be updated when you change the heading text,
sequence, or level.
Highlight the text you wish to apply a heading to,
then navigate to the Home tab,
and in the style galleries, select the heading choice
and the text automatically takes that heading form.
If you have subheadings,
select different texts that you would like to have
under the first heading and apply a different style to it.
Now you're ready to create and add your table of contents.
Now place your cursor
where you want to insert the table of contents.
I usually place it near the beginning of the document
or after a title page.
On the top ribbon, select References.
Next, select Table of Contents.
In the dropdown menu, choose Insert Table of Contents.
If you make changes to your document
that affect the table of contents,
you can update it by selecting the table
and selecting the update box that appears
to the left of the table of contents.
Adding references as footnotes
and creating a table of contents
is a great way of elevating your documents.
Try adding these reference forms to your next document.