- [Instructor] Adding data to your documents can make
or break its usefulness.
It can make your content more compelling
or just confuse your audience
if it's not displayed accurately.
Word makes sharing data in an organized manner an easy task.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you how to create
and edit tables to ensure every team member
can easily review the data you present.
To get started, I'll open my Word document
from the Microsoft 365 homepage.
Follow along by downloading the sample Word document
in your Exercise Files.
It's called Customer Event Itinerary Example B.
In this example, I'll show you how to insert a table
for organizing an event schedule into a Word document.
Tables are useful to present
and organize detailed information, such as cost figures,
a guest list of names, or inventory.
To insert a basic table, start by placing your cursor
where you want the table to be in your document.
I'll start at the top of the document
underneath Itinerary for day of event details.
Next, select Insert from the top ribbon, then select Table.
And move the cursor over the grid until the number of cells
in the rows and columns you need is highlighted.
Selected, and the table will appear in your document.
Now, you can type directly into it.
To adjust it and apply formatting, hover over your table
and select the four way directional arrows
in the top left corner.
You can choose to change the font
of all the texts in the table, apply any styles,
incorporate cell shading,
and add or remove columns or rows.
More editing and formatting options
can be found by navigating to the top ribbon
and selecting Table.
To highlight and organize your data, select Table Styles.
You can also split cells, add borders,
or even change the colors of the cells and table itself.
This looks pretty good, but before I share this table,
I want to make sure that it is inclusive
and can be read out loud to people who use a screen reader
or have different abilities.
To check the accessibility of the table,
first, I'll navigate all the way through the table
using only the Tab key.
If you can tap through the table
cell by cell and row by row,
a screen reader should have no trouble with it.
You can also use the Accessibility Checker
to get suggestions
on how to make your document more accessible.
Navigate to the top ribbon and select Review.
Then select Check Accessibility.
Word will open the Accessibility Checker on the right side
of the screen with a list of errors and warnings,
as well as a list of tips on how to fix each issue.
When you choose an item from the inspection results,
Word displays that part of the document.
Below the inspection results, Word explains why
and how to fix the issue you've selected.
After you make all the necessary changes,
your document will be more accessible to everyone.
I encourage you to add a table and check for accessibility
in the next document you create.
Your data will appear more organized
and easier to understand.
Way to go!