- [Instructor] One of the most effective uses of mail merge
is creating labels for mass communication.
It adds a nice touch of professionalism
when mailings are addressed easily and properly.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you ways to use Word
and Excel to create a mail merge
for generating your own labels.
Please note that the mail merge feature is only available
in the desktop version.
To get started, I'll open a blank Microsoft Word document
and select mailings from the top ribbon.
Next, select start mail merge
and then the step by step mail merge wizard.
The mail merge wizard takes you through the process
of creating labels step by step.
When the mail merge panel opens on the right side
of the screen, select labels then select
next, starting document.
Select label options, then look up the label vendor
and product number for your physical labels and select OK.
To view the label grid, go to the Layout tab
on the top ribbon and select view grid lines.
Then move on to the next step
by selecting next, select recipients.
Follow along by downloading the list in the exercise file,
it's called example contact list.
Select browse to find your recipient list Excel document,
then select Open.
In the next window, make sure the first row of data
contains column headers box is selected and select OK.
This lets Word know that the first row
does not contain mailing information for your labels.
Now you can check your list
and when you're sure everything is correct select OK.
Select next arrange your labels
when you're ready to move on.
Add the appropriate address information
by selecting address block and view how the addresses
will appear in the insert address block window.
You can preview each recipient
by going through the arrows at the top of the box.
If the data isn't going into the labels correctly,
try editing the match fields to make sure
the appropriate headings line up.
For example, first name needs to align
with the first name heading and address one
with the billing address and so on and so forth.
Once you've confirmed everything is correct, select OK,
and update all labels and then move on to the next step,
preview your labels.
Finally, you're ready to complete the mail merge
by selecting next, complete the mail merge.
Now you're ready to print your labels,
select print and select if you want to print all
or some of the labels and then select, OK.
You can select OK again if all printer information
is accurate and your labels will print out.
Setting up labels takes a few steps, but once it's complete,
you've set yourself up for success
and all your labeling needs are addressed.
Try creating labels or envelopes
for your next mailing project.