- [Narrator] Working with outside organizations
is a part of collaboration
and it's important to make any partnership experience
as seamless as possible.
In Teams, guests can participate in meetings,
chats, and work on documents.
In this lesson, I'll show you how to invite external guests
and manage the settings and permissions
needed to work with them in Teams.
To get started, I'll open Teams
from the Microsoft 365 homepage.
First, I'll select the team I want to add guests to.
In that team, I'll select more options
to the right of the name of that team.
And then I'll select Add member.
Here, I'll enter my guest email addresses.
When I'm done selecting all the guests,
select Add and the guests will be sent an email invitation.
A guest will have the label Guest attached to their name
wherever it's displayed in Microsoft Teams.
You can also check the top of any channel
to see how many guests are in it
by selecting the information icon in the top right.
To close it, select the information icon again.
To set specific guest access,
select next to the team name for more options.
From there, select Manage team.
In the Settings tab, select the Guest permissions dropdown
to select or clear options or permissions
that you want to use.
Well done.
Now you're ready to add external guests
and set specific permissions for them.
You'll be collaborating in no time.